<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Clinical Brain Lab</title>
    <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The Clinical Brain Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to the New Website!</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/blog/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/blog/welcome/</guid>
      <description>Hi everyone! We&amp;rsquo;ve just shifted from the old CBL website to a github-based one to allow for easier collaboration and resource-sharing!
As there are several ongoing projects in the lab, we believe it will be more efficient in the long-run if everyone gets on board with updating the website, be it modifying your profile, adding new publications, or putting up recruitment calls for research participants - and hosting the website on GitHub will be the most optimal in achieving this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cerebro-cerebellar pathways for verbal working memory</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/cc-pathway/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 16:03:15 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/cc-pathway/</guid>
      <description>Verbal working memory involves holding verbal information in short-term memory. Two cerebro-cerebellar networks for verbal working memory have been proposed: (1) fronto-superior cerebellar network associated with controlling and updating speech-related information, and (2) parieto-inferior cerebellar network associated with storing speech-related information briefly. Sobczak-Edmans and colleagues (2019) examined the structural and functional connectivity of these cerebro-cerebellar networks. Using diffusion spectrum imaging tractography, they reconstructed white matter tracts in: (1) the left inferior frontal gyrus via the pons to the right superior cerebellum, and (2) the left inferior parietal lobule via the pons to the right inferior cerebellum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indices of Effect Existence and Significance in the Bayesian Framework</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/bayesian-framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 16:03:15 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/bayesian-framework/</guid>
      <description>The Bayesian framework is increasingly believed to address some issues with the frequentist framework, especially the misuse and misinterpretation of p-values that has contributed to the reproducibility crisis. While the Bayesian framework offers several alternative indices for the frequentist p-value, there is a lack of consensus and guidelines to help researchers decide which indices to use and understand the meaning of the values. Makowski and colleagues (2019) compared several Bayesian indices by simulating two widely used models in psychological sciences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Structure of Deception: Validation of the Lying Profile Questionnaire</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/deception-scale/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 16:03:15 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/deception-scale/</guid>
      <description>While deception is considered as a common phenomenon with important implications, its conceptualization and study as a dispositional trait is under-represented in the literature. Critically, and despite scientific evidence supporting the existence of individual differences in lying, a validated measure of dispositional deception is still lacking. This study aims to explore the structure of dispositional deception by developing and validating a short and reliable 16-item questionnaire to characterize the lying pattern of individuals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Translating education neuroscience for teachers</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/translate-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 16:03:15 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/translate-education/</guid>
      <description>Translating Neuroscience to education involves providing accurate and simplified information about neuroscience to teachers. The aim of this research was to understand if providing translated abstracts from neuroscientific articles helped teachers understand content more thoroughly. Surveys, experimental manipulation, and focus group discussions were conducted with thirty teachers from two primary schools in Singapore. Teachers shared their familiarity with neuroscience, self-rated their understanding of neuroscientific abstracts, and provided feedback on the abstracts’ translations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conferences</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/events/conferences/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 12:57:28 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/events/conferences/</guid>
      <description> OHBM Rome 2019  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Join Us</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/join/doctoral-fellowships/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 12:57:28 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/join/doctoral-fellowships/</guid>
      <description>Doctorate Research Fellowship We are currently actively recruiting for PhD students interested in developing research in educational neuroscience, affective neuroscience and aging neuroscience (specifically in older neurological patients). These fellowships will be held in the Clinical Brain Laboratory, Division of Psychology, Nanyang Technological University (NTU), Singapore.
Scope Research in the lab is focused on the neural basis of higher cognition in the cerebellum, cognitive training in healthy aging and we will be developing an area in Educational Neuroscience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Join Us</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/join/post-doctoral/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 12:57:28 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/join/post-doctoral/</guid>
      <description>Post-doctoral Research Fellowships/Research Fellow We are currently seeking highly motivated individuals who share our passion in deciphering the enigma of the brain to join us at the Clinical Brain Lab , Nanyang Technological University! We are seeking candidates interested in educational neuroscience.
Aim We are interested in building capacity for research in the Science of Learning, in particular in the area of educational neuroscience. We seek to understand how cognitive neuroscience can be applied to education to optimize learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Join Us</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/join/system-administrator/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 12:57:28 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/join/system-administrator/</guid>
      <description>Part-time System Administrator The Clinical Brain Lab housed within the Division of Psychology at NTU is seeking a part-time system administrator to help with setting up and maintaining networked servers used for image analyses within the lab. The main research focus of the lab is studying brain functions using neuroimaging methods.
Who can apply Graduate or undergraduate students may apply. It is an hourly position or 8-10 hours per week (negotiable).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Participate</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/participate/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 12:57:28 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/participate/</guid>
      <description> We are actively looking for participants to take part in our experiments.
Investigating the Bilingual Reading Network Please contact biliteracystudy@gmail.com for more information.
 Measuring the brain response to non-invasive brain stimulation Please contact agoodwill@ntu.edu.sg for more information.
 Studying the experience of COVID-19 News Perception Please contact zenjuen.lau@ntu.edu.sg for more information
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>People</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/people/graduate-student/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 12:57:28 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/people/graduate-student/</guid>
      <description>Graduate Students Gladys Heng, B.A. Ph.D. Student Division of Psychology, School of Social Sciences Nanyang Technological University
(To-be-added)
 Academic Profile: ResearchGate Email: jheng007@e.ntu.edu.sg  
 Dayton Leow, B.A. (Hons) Ph.D. Student Division of Psychology, School of Social Sciences Nanyang Technological University
(To-be-added)
 Academic Profile: ResearchGate Email: H160040@e.ntu.edu.sg  
 Dr. Sagarika Bhattacharjee, M.D., M.B.B.S Ph.D. Student Division of Psychology, School of Social Sciences Nanyang Technological University</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>People</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/people/prof-annabel/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 12:57:28 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/people/prof-annabel/</guid>
      <description>Principal Investigator, Lab Director SH Annabel Chen, PhD Dr. SH Annabel Chen is a clinical neuropsychologist, and currently a Faculty member of Psychology at the School of Social Sciences, LKCMedicine and Acting Director of the Centre for Research and Development in Learning (CRADLE), at the Nanyang Technological University.
After obtaining her PhD in Clinical Rehabilitation Psychology from Purdue University and completing a Clinical Psychology Internship at West Virginia University School of Medicine, she continued with a post-doctoral residency in Clinical Neuropsychology at the Department of Neurology, Medical College of Wisconsin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>People</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/people/research-crew/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 12:57:28 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/people/research-crew/</guid>
      <description>Research Crew Ilang Kumaran Yuvadarshini Research Associate Centre for Research and Development in Learning (CRADLE) Nanyang Technological University
(To-be-added)
 Email: yuvakumaran@ntu.edu.sg  
 Pham Thanh Tam, B.A. (Hons) Project Officer Division of Psychology, School of Social Sciences Nanyang Technological University
(To-be-added)
 Academic Profile: ResearchGate Email: phamtt@ntu.edu.sg  
 Lin Hsin-Yu Research Associate Centre for Research and Development in Learning (CRADLE) Nanyang Technological University
(To-be-added)
 Email: linhy@ntu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>People</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/people/research-fellow/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 12:57:28 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/people/research-fellow/</guid>
      <description>Research Scientists and Research Fellows Chiao-Yi Wu, Ph.D. Research Scientist Centre for Research and Development in Learning (CRADLE) Nanyang Technological University
(To-be-added)
 Academic Profile: NTU Website, ResearchGate Email: cywu@ntu.edu.sg  
 Alicia Goodwill, Ph.D.  Research Scientist Centre for Research and Development in Learning (CRADLE) Nanyang Technological University
(To-be-added)
 Academic Profile: NTU Website, ResearchGate Email: agoodwill@ntu.edu.sg  
 Rajan Kashyap, Ph.D. Research Fellow Centre for Research and Development in Learning (CRADLE) Nanyang Technological University</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>People</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/people/system-admin/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 12:57:28 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/people/system-admin/</guid>
      <description> Systems Administrator Chung Sheng Hung, MEngSc Systems Administrator  Email: shchung@ntu.edu.sg  
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>People</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/people/undergraduate-student/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 12:57:28 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/people/undergraduate-student/</guid>
      <description> Undergraduate Students Low Jia Rong, B.A. (Hons) Final Year Student Division of Psychology, School of Social Sciences Nanyang Technological University
(to-be added)
 Email: jlow052@e.ntu.edu.sg   Elaine Teo, BSc. (Hons) First Year Student Division of Psychology and Language Sciences, Faculty of Brain Sciences University College London
(to-be added)
 Email: elaine.teo.19@ucl.ac.uk  
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Visits</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/events/research-visits/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 12:57:28 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/events/research-visits/</guid>
      <description>John Hopkins University (JHU) Research Visit by the CBL Team</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visiting Professors</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/events/visiting-professors/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 12:57:28 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/events/visiting-professors/</guid>
      <description>Visiting Professor Daniel Ansari, Professor Edward Wilding and Professor Shahid Bashir at our lab meeting on the 20th July 2017</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/home/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 12:01:05 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/home/about/</guid>
      <description>Our brain plays an important role in how we perceive and interact with the world around us. What happens when development goes awry in our brain, or insult occurs to our brain? How do we harness neuroplasticity to ameliorate neuropsychiatric conditions, or to optimize learning during the natural progression of neurodegeneration? Can we enhance cognitive health through neuromodulations?
At the Clinical Brain lab, we apply clinical neuropsychological principles to uncover the enigma of the brain and work towards addressing these questions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description> Address  Division of Psychology School of Social Sciences Nanyang Technological University 14 Nanyang Drive Singapore 637332  Find us  clinicalbrainlab@gmail.com 
 Facebook
 Twitter
 Github
Find out more about the Division of Psychology at Nayang Technological University (NTU)
 </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>