<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Clinical Brain Lab</title>
    <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>The Clinical Brain Lab</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2030 13:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/images/icon_hu30d0ad82a56c1708370149d7b9443316_148842_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>The Clinical Brain Lab</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Example Talk</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/talk/example/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2030 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/talk/example/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Click on the &lt;strong&gt;Slides&lt;/strong&gt; button above to view the built-in slides feature.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides can be added in a few ways:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create&lt;/strong&gt; slides using Academic&amp;rsquo;s 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/managing-content/#create-slides&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Slides&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; feature and link using &lt;code&gt;slides&lt;/code&gt; parameter in the front matter of the talk file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Upload&lt;/strong&gt; an existing slide deck to &lt;code&gt;static/&lt;/code&gt; and link using &lt;code&gt;url_slides&lt;/code&gt; parameter in the front matter of the talk file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Embed&lt;/strong&gt; your slides (e.g. Google Slides) or presentation video on this page using 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;shortcodes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further talk details can easily be added to this page using &lt;em&gt;Markdown&lt;/em&gt; and $\rm \LaTeX$ math code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Structure of Deception: Validation of the Lying Profile Questionnaire</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2020_deception-scale/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2020_deception-scale/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Volunteers Needed!</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/post/dyslexia-biliteracy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/post/dyslexia-biliteracy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./dyslexia-biliteracy-poster.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The role of primary motor cortex: More than movement execution</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2020_m1-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2020_m1-review/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indices of effect existence and significance in the Bayesian framework</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2019_bayesian/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2019_bayesian/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maximizing dissimilarity in resting state detects heterogeneous subtypes in healthy population associated with high substance use and problems in antisocial personality</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2020_rsfmri-subtypes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2020_rsfmri-subtypes/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Translating education neuroscience for teachers</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2019_translating/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2019_translating/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brain literacy empowers educators to meet diverse learner needs</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2019_brain-literacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2019_brain-literacy/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doctorate Research Fellowship</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/join/join2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/join/join2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are currently actively recruiting for PhD students interested in developing research in educational neuroscience, affective neuroscience and aging neuroscience (specifically in older neurological patients).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;job-scope&#34;&gt;Job Scope&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research in the lab is focused on the neural basis of higher cognition in the cerebellum, cognitive training in healthy aging and we will be developing an area in Educational Neuroscience. Main research modalities in our lab include: neuropsychological assessments, cognitive tests, functional Magnetic Resonance (fMRI), diffusion MRI (DTI, HARDI, DSI), EEG and Transcranial Magnetic Stimulation (TMS). The candidate will be expected to conduct research in areas noted above, especially using diffusion MRI. However, he/she is also encouraged to develop own related research topic of interest. For more information about the lab please click 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://portal.hss.ntu.edu.sg/annalab/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;looking-for&#34;&gt;Looking For&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We welcome applicants with a &lt;strong&gt;Bachelors&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;Masters degree&lt;/strong&gt; in various backgrounds such as: &lt;strong&gt;experimental psychology, biopsychology, cognitive psychology, neuropsychology, neurology, psychiatry, cognitive neuroscience, electrical engineering, medical engineering, computer science&lt;/strong&gt;, and related fields.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The successful applicant will be enrolled in the graduate psychology program by research. For non-local degree holders, GRE exams (general and subject) will be required for application. Find out more about the 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://psychology.hss.ntu.edu.sg/Programmes/Graduate/Pages/DoctorofPhilosophy.aspx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Graduate Program&lt;/a&gt; and its 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://admissions.ntu.edu.sg/graduate/R-Programs/Pages/default.aspx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Online Application&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;apply&#34;&gt;Apply&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please address questions or send Curriculum Vita to &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:annabelchen@ntu.edu.sg&#34;&gt;annabelchen@ntu.edu.sg&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Electroencephalogram</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/resources/techniques/eeg/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/resources/techniques/eeg/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-eeg&#34;&gt;What is EEG?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EEG (Electroencephalogram) is a neuroimaging technique used to measure electrical activity at the scalp that reflects the neural activity in the brain. It is a real-time recording of neural activity with millisecond temporal resolution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./EEG_Recording.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-is-an-eeg-done&#34;&gt;How is an EEG Done?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EEG is a completely safe and non-invasive technique. There is no exposure to any form of external x-rays or radiation. To record the EEG signals, an EEG cap would be put over the head and connected to an amplifier which would allow us to see the brain waves on a computer screen.
Electrolytic gel is inserted into the small plastic holders in the cap to improve the conductance between the electrodes and the scalp.
Separate electrodes may also be directly attached to the skin (such as above and below the eyes) using electrode tape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./IMG-20150628-WA0008.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-eeg-used-for&#34;&gt;What is EEG used for?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the Clinical Brain Lab NTU, we are using EEG to measure changes in brain activity after cognitive training or during cognitive tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Functional Magnetic Resonance Imaging</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/resources/techniques/fmri/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/resources/techniques/fmri/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-fmri&#34;&gt;What is fMRI?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;fMRI is a safe, noninvasive imaging technology. Unlike x-rays, which use ionizing radiation, fMRI images are generated from a strong magnetic field and low-power radio-waves.
Therefore, there is no risk of exposure to radiation in fMRI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-use-fmri&#34;&gt;Why use fMRI?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;fMRI allows researchers to obtain images of brain activity over time, as participants complete various tasks.
From these images, researchers get a better understanding of the brain areas that are involved in the tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./3TMRI_aging.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Functional Near-Infrared Spectroscopy</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/resources/techniques/fnirs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/resources/techniques/fnirs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-fnirs&#34;&gt;What is fNIRS?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;fNIRS (functional near-infrared spectroscopy) is a non-invasive neuroimaging technique that measures brain responses by recording changes in the amount of oxygenated/deoxygenated blood.
It works based on the principle of light scattering – the device sends high intensity beams of near-infrared light at the scalp and detects changes to amount of light absorbed within the brain.
Mathematical algorithms are then applied to process the collected data to calculate changes in oxygenated/deoxygenated haemoglobin concentration. These changes are associated with changes in brain function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./fNIRS2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-is-fnirs-done&#34;&gt;How is fNIRS Done?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;fNIRS is a non-invasive neuroimaging technique that does not require any exposure to radiation or x-rays. To record signals, a fNIRS cap is fitted over the participant’s head.
The optodes (sources and detectors) are then attached onto the cap. To ensure the optodes sit directly on the scalp, the participant’s hair may be moved to the side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./fNIRS3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-fnirs-used-for&#34;&gt;What is fNIRS used for?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently in our lab, we are using fNIRS to explore changes in brain activity during brain stimulation and during cognitive tasks – i.e. reading.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Post-doctoral Research Fellowships/Research Fellow</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/join/join1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/join/join1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are currently seeking highly motivated individuals who share our passion in deciphering the enigma of the brain to join us at the Clinical Brain Lab , Nanyang Technological University! We are seeking candidates interested in educational neuroscience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;job-scope&#34;&gt;Job Scope&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are interested in building capacity for research in the &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Science of Learning&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, in particular in the area of educational neuroscience. We seek to understand how cognitive neuroscience can be applied to education to optimize learning. The successful candidate will work closely with researchers at the Centre for Research and Development in Learning (
&lt;a href=&#34;https://cradle.ntu.edu.sg/Pages/home.aspx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CRADLE&lt;/a&gt;), National Institute of Education (
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nie.edu.sg/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;NIE&lt;/a&gt;), and other international collaborators from institutes such as Johns Hopkins University, Massachusetts Institute of Technology and/or University of Cambridge. The &lt;strong&gt;current project will be investigating reading brain networks in bilingual children&lt;/strong&gt;. Singapore is a multicultural city that has a conducive education system to study this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main research modalities in our lab include: neuropsychological assessments, cognitive tests, functional Magnetic Resonance (fMRI), diffusion MRI (DTI, HARDI, DSI), electroencephalography (EEG), Transcranial Magnetic Stimulation (TMS).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;looking-for&#34;&gt;Looking For&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We welcome applicants with a &lt;strong&gt;doctorate (PhD)&lt;/strong&gt; degree in various backgrounds such as:
&lt;strong&gt;experimental psychology, biopsychology, cognitive psychology, neuropsychology, neurology,
psychiatry, cognitive neuroscience, electrical engineering, medical engineering, computer science&lt;/strong&gt;, and related fields.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;requirements&#34;&gt;Requirements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Candidates are expected to have good interpersonal skills and to have demonstrated record of excellent scientific writing skills. Desirable qualification includes one or more of the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experience with conducting behavioral experiments in neuropsychology or cognitive psychology.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experience with neuroimaging techniques (MRI/EEG/or TMS).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Familiarity with image data analysis tools such as SPM, FSL, AFNI, DSIStudio, Matlab, Python etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;apply&#34;&gt;Apply&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To apply, please send Curriculum Vitae, letter of application with research interests, and three letters of recommendation to &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:annabelchen@ntu.edu.sg&#34;&gt;annabelchen@ntu.edu.sg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contact information&lt;/strong&gt;: Professor S.H. Annabel Chen, PhD, Psychology, School of Social Sciences, Nanyang Technological University, 14 Nanyang Drive, HSS‐04‐19, Singapore 637332, phone +65‐6316‐8836.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transcranial Direct Current Stimulation</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/resources/techniques/tdcs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/resources/techniques/tdcs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-tdcs&#34;&gt;What is tDCS?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;tDCS (Transcranial Direct Current Stimulation) is a non-invasive and relatively painless brain stimulation technique that adjusts regional brain activity through modulating the transmembrane potential of neurons by sending low amplitude direct-current into the scalp.
In healthy populations, anodal tDCS has been shown to increase cortical excitability while cathodal tDCS has been shown to inhibit cortical excitability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./tDCS.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-is-tdcs-done&#34;&gt;How is tDCS Done?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The electrode to be used is inserted into saline soaked sponges. The region where the electrode is to be placed is first wiped clean with alcohol wipes. Hair is then parted and the sponge is positioned over the marked position and secured in place using rubber straps.
When ready, the experimenter uses the DC-stimulator to start the stimulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-tdcs-used-for&#34;&gt;What is tDCS used for?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently in our lab, we are investigating effects of tDCS on cognitive tasks (e.g. reading) and exploring changes in brain activity as a result of tDCS using fNIRS.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transcranial Magnetic Stimulation</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/resources/techniques/tms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/resources/techniques/tms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-tms&#34;&gt;What is TMS?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TMS (Transcranial Magnetic Stimulation) is a non-invasive and painless tool that modulates neural activity. It works on the principle of Faraday’s law of electromagnetic induction.
In TMS, an electromagnetic coil sends a perpendicular magnetic field into the region of interest on the scalp. This field indirectly influences neuronal activity. TMS has been shown in some cases to induce cortical excitability and in some cases to depress excitability.
TMS can be administered in bursts at a rhythmic frequency (repetitive TMS) or as a single pulse. Repetitive TMS has been shown to have a greater and lasting effect. Depending on the question, rapid or slow repetitive TMS can be administered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-is-tms-done&#34;&gt;How is TMS Done?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An electromyography (EMG) module is first attached via a wristband and by pasting electrodes onto the participant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./TMS1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After setting up the parameters, an experimenter positions the magnetic coil above the participant’s scalp, over the region of interest. When activated, a high-current pulse is produced in the TMS coil, inducing a perpendicular magnetic field.
As high-current pulses are sent through the coil, the participant may hear clicks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./TMS2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-tms-used-for&#34;&gt;What is TMS used for?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TMS can be used to treat clinical conditions (such as drug-resistant depression) or be used as an experimental technique to understand brain functions. In our lab, we are applying fMRI-guided TMS to target regions of the brain to determine its involvement in various cognitive networks.
We are also combining it with EEG to understand neuroplasticity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slides</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/slides/example/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/slides/example/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;create-slides-in-markdown-with-academic&#34;&gt;Create slides in Markdown with Academic&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Academic&lt;/a&gt; | 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/managing-content/#create-slides&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;features&#34;&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Efficiently write slides in Markdown&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3-in-1: Create, Present, and Publish your slides&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supports speaker notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mobile friendly slides&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;controls&#34;&gt;Controls&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Next: &lt;code&gt;Right Arrow&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;Space&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Previous: &lt;code&gt;Left Arrow&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start: &lt;code&gt;Home&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finish: &lt;code&gt;End&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overview: &lt;code&gt;Esc&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speaker notes: &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fullscreen: &lt;code&gt;F&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zoom: &lt;code&gt;Alt + Click&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/hakimel/reveal.js#pdf-export&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PDF Export&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;code&gt;E&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;code-highlighting&#34;&gt;Code Highlighting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inline code: &lt;code&gt;variable&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Code block:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;porridge = &amp;quot;blueberry&amp;quot;
if porridge == &amp;quot;blueberry&amp;quot;:
    print(&amp;quot;Eating...&amp;quot;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;math&#34;&gt;Math&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In-line math: $x + y = z$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Block math:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$$
f\left( x \right) = ;\frac{{2\left( {x + 4} \right)\left( {x - 4} \right)}}{{\left( {x + 4} \right)\left( {x + 1} \right)}}
$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fragments&#34;&gt;Fragments&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make content appear incrementally&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{{% fragment %}} One {{% /fragment %}}
{{% fragment %}} **Two** {{% /fragment %}}
{{% fragment %}} Three {{% /fragment %}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Press &lt;code&gt;Space&lt;/code&gt; to play!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
One
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Two&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
Three
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A fragment can accept two optional parameters:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;class&lt;/code&gt;: use a custom style (requires definition in custom CSS)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;weight&lt;/code&gt;: sets the order in which a fragment appears&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;speaker-notes&#34;&gt;Speaker Notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add speaker notes to your presentation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34;&gt;{{% speaker_note %}}
- Only the speaker can read these notes
- Press `S` key to view
{{% /speaker_note %}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Press the &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt; key to view the speaker notes!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only the speaker can read these notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Press &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt; key to view&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;themes&#34;&gt;Themes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;black: Black background, white text, blue links (default)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;white: White background, black text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;league: Gray background, white text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;beige: Beige background, dark text, brown links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sky: Blue background, thin dark text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;night: Black background, thick white text, orange links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;serif: Cappuccino background, gray text, brown links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;simple: White background, black text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;solarized: Cream-colored background, dark green text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;section data-noprocess data-shortcode-slide
  
      
      data-background-image=&#34;/media/boards.jpg&#34;
  &gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;custom-slide&#34;&gt;Custom Slide&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Customize the slide style and background&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34;&gt;{{&amp;lt; slide background-image=&amp;quot;/media/boards.jpg&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}}
{{&amp;lt; slide background-color=&amp;quot;#0000FF&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}}
{{&amp;lt; slide class=&amp;quot;my-style&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;custom-css-example&#34;&gt;Custom CSS Example&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s make headers navy colored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create &lt;code&gt;assets/css/reveal_custom.css&lt;/code&gt; with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-css&#34;&gt;.reveal section h1,
.reveal section h2,
.reveal section h3 {
  color: navy;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;questions&#34;&gt;Questions?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://spectrum.chat/academic&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Ask&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/managing-content/#create-slides&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cerebro-cerebellar pathways for verbal working memory</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2019_cerebro-cerebellar/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2019_cerebro-cerebellar/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working memory, age and education: A lifespan fMRI study</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2018_aging-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2018_aging-education/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Functional connectivity of resting-state, working memory and inhibition networks in perceived stress</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2018_stress/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2018_stress/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The role of regional heterogeneity in age-related differences in functional hemispheric asymmetry: an fMRI study</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2018_aging-asymmetry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2018_aging-asymmetry/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biliteracy</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/biliteracy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/biliteracy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our research on biliteracy aims to better understand neural networks and the cognitive mechanisms underlying bilingualism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;measuring-the-brain-response-to-non-invasive-brain-stimulation&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Measuring the brain response to non-invasive brain stimulation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently in our lab, we are using fNIRS to explore changes in brain activity during brain stimulation and during cognitive tasks – i.e. reading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;fNIRS (functional near-infrared spectroscopy) is a non-invasive neuroimaging technique that measures brain responses by recording changes in the amount of oxygenated/deoxygenated blood. It works based on the principle of light scattering – the device sends high intensity beams of near-infrared light at the scalp and detects changes to amount of light absorbed within the brain. Mathematical algorithms are then applied to process the collected data to calculate changes in oxygenated/deoxygenated haemoglobin concentration. These changes are associated with changes in brain function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our project is activey looking for participants to take part!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./fNIRS-tDCS.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;investigating-the-bilingual-reading-network&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Investigating the Bilingual Reading Network&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chinese-English Bilinguals who had a history of dyslexia or are struggling in reading&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./biliteracy-dyslexia.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cerebellum and Cognition</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/cerebellum/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/cerebellum/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Description&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inter-individual Differences in Deception Profile</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/deception-neuroscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/deception-neuroscience/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While deception is considered as a common phenomenon with important implications, its conceptualization and study as a dispositional trait is under-represented in the literature. Critically, and despite scientific evidence supporting the existence of individual differences in lying, a validated measure of dispositional deception is still lacking. This study aims to explore the structure of dispositional deception by developing and validating a short and reliable 16-item questionnaire to characterize individuals&amp;rsquo; lying patterns. Our findings suggest the existence of four distinct latent dimensions to lying, namely frequency, ability, negativity, and contextuality. We establish the convergent validity of our measure of lying by showing significant relationships with social desirability, malevolent traits, cognitive control deficits, normal and pathological personality traits, as well as demographic variables such as sex, age, and religiosity. Overall, the present study introduces a general framework to understanding deception as a dispositional trait which future deception studies can build on, accounting for the inter-individual variability in lying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study is pre-registered and currently submitted for review.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
