<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dominique Makowski | The Clinical Brain Lab</title>
    <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/author/dominique-makowski/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/author/dominique-makowski/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Dominique Makowski</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/images/icon_hu30d0ad82a56c1708370149d7b9443316_148842_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Dominique Makowski</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/author/dominique-makowski/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perception of Real vs. Fake Information</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/fake-news/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/fake-news/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Deception, or in other words, information that does not reflect reality, created or delivered with the intention of duping the receiver, is increasingly prevalent in the age of social media. With virtual reality, augmented reality, uncontrolled mass communication, and new forms of fiction, it becomes increasingly difficult to separate truth from deception. Moreover, brain mechanisms and other physiological correlates underlying the processing and acceptance of deceptive information remain largely unknown. This study will be a critical first step in understanding how deceitful information becomes endorsed by individuals susceptible to fake news beliefs and conspiracy theories, consequently facilitating counteract measures in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first aim of this study is to establish and validate a strong experimental paradigm for investigating the neurocognitive processes underlying the belief in deceptive (i.e., Fake/Real) information. It should be noted that real and fake in this study is defined by the factual accuracy of the information based on current credible news. The second aim is to investigate how these processes can be experimentally modulated and the extent of their impact on one&amp;rsquo;s deception appraisal. This paradigm will then help to build a computational model of reality belief which in turn will be used to predict the effect of specific interventions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brain entropy, fractal dimensions and predictability: A review of complexity measures for EEG in healthy and neuropsychiatric populations</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2022_brain-entropy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2022_brain-entropy/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Structure of Chaos: An Empirical Comparison of Fractal Physiology Complexity Indices Using NeuroKit2</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2022_structure-of-chaos/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2022_structure-of-chaos/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Closer Look at Cardiac Contraction and the Effect of Cardiac Timing on Cognitive Control</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2022_cocon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2022_cocon/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fractal Dimensions of EEG Activity is Linked to Distinct Facets of Resting-State Cognition</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2022_restingstatecomplexity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2022_restingstatecomplexity/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brain Entropy, Fractal Dimensions and Predictability: A Review of Complexity Measures for EEG in Healthy and Neuropsychiatric Populations</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2021_braincomplexity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2021_braincomplexity/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Parametric Framework to Generate Visual Illusions using Python</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2021_pyllusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2021_pyllusion/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heart Rate Variability in Psychology: A Review of HRV Indices and an Analysis Tutorial</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2021_hrv/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2021_hrv/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Structure of Deception: Validation of the Lying Profile Questionnaire</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2020_deception-scale/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2020_deception-scale/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NeuroKit2: A Python toolbox for neurophysiological signal processing</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2021_neurokit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2021_neurokit/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Psychological Determinants of the Susceptibility to Fake News amidst the COVID-19 Pandemic</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2020_deception-covid-fakenews/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2020_deception-covid-fakenews/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As the COVID-19 outbreak spreads across the globe, the world is in parallel flooded by information reporting a wide range of facts, which veracity is not always verifiable.
Indeed, it has become increasingly apparent that the COVID-19 fake news pandemic is becoming just as viral as the outbreak of the disease itself, evidenced by the need for researchers
and authorities to track the spread of misinformation. As a consequence, the Ministry of Health in Singapore has even dedicated an entire website (See here: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.moh.gov.sg/covid-19/clarifications&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://www.moh.gov.sg/covid-19/clarifications&lt;/a&gt;) to debunk all instances of fake news.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-role-of-conspiracy-theories&#34;&gt;The Role of Conspiracy Theories&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the authorities are struggling to provide concrete explanations about the coronavirus, conspiracy theorists are quick to provide competing ones with confidence.
This has exaggerated the spread of fake news and conspiracy theories - beliefs that seek to explain the cause of an event by a hidden, wicked and unlawful scheme, without scientific support.
For instance, a theory that the new 5G technology causes the spread of coronavirus outbreak was widely circulated and peddled by conspiracy theorists.
Studies have shown that conspiracy theories are often endorsed by people who feel powerless. Their rejection of mainstream accounts and adoption of conspiracy explanations is an attempt to make sense of the world beyond their control (Swami &amp;amp; Furnham, 2010).
The uncertainties brought about by the COVID-19 pandemic might prompt people, especially individuals with higher schizotypal tendencies (characterized by suspicion, social anxiety and paranoid ideation), to engage in this sense-making mechanism, seeking alternative explanations
to regain their sense of control. People who have the tendency to adopt conspiracy theories have been found to rely more on intuition (Pennycook, Cheyne, Barr, Koehler &amp;amp; Fugelsang, 2015; Pennycook &amp;amp; Rand, 2018) and are hence more susceptible to fake news beliefs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-role-of-emotions&#34;&gt;The Role of Emotions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a global pandemic where the world is in a constant elevated state of anxiety, fake news beliefs can befall anyone for reasons beyond just the persistent cognitive biases that characterize conspiracist theorists.
People are often left feeling fearful and anxious due to the endless bombardment of pandemic news information, regardless of its accuracy.
Fake news on COVID-19 are especially emotionally engaging because they play on people’s helplessness by offering some miracle remedy or fueling anger towards authorities handling the situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A research team led by Gordon Pennycook, a researcher on the psychology of misinformation, found that individuals are more likely to perceive fake news headlines as accurate when they were in an emotional state (Martel et al., 2019). At the Clinical Brain Lab, we have started research into this area during the
Circuit Breaker period. We propose that the underlying factor driving susceptibility to fake news beliefs is not just the mere presence of negative affect, but how one regulates these emotions.
This refers to the ability to control one’s emotional state, such as considering alternative interpretations of an otherwise negative situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the context of the COVID-19 pandemic, an important aspect of emotion regulation is being able to navigate through the uncertainties of the future. With future plans now at a standstill and emotions running high, we become less tolerant of uncertainty and feel more helpless about our circumstances.
Poor self-control makes us cognitively lazy, believing something because “it feels right” and aligned with our emotions. Fast, intuitive processing thus often takes precedence over effortful and reflective thinking, of which the latter is needed to discern whether a piece of news is real or fake (Pennycook &amp;amp; Rand, 2019).
We are thus more vulnerable to engaging in fake news than we think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;our-research&#34;&gt;Our Research&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As it is important to delineate the psychological determinants of the belief in fake news as part of a global effort in combating misinformation, Prof Annabel Chen together with Research Fellow Dr Dominique Makowski and research assistants (Pham Thanh Tam and Lau Zen Juen) are currently conducting an investigation into the spread of COVID-19 fake news in Singapore.
Specifically, this study seeks to examine whether the belief in conspiracy theories and one’s ability to regulate emotions are related to one’s tendency to fall prey to fake news.
This study is pre-registered at 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://osf.io/7d3xh/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;OSF&lt;/a&gt; and currently undergoing data analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Behavioural and Neural Correlates of Deception</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/deception/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/deception/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Traditional lie detection as used in polygraph test is based on examining one&amp;rsquo;s physiological arousal (measuring skin conductance,
heart rate, and respiration) to infer lying. However, such physiological arousal may merely be reflecting anxiety and fear during a polygraph examination,
rather than lying per se.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As physiological arousal could not be used to accurately infer lying, researchers are urged to further look into the mental processes related to lying.
To date, different neurophysiological signals, including functional magnetic resonance imaging (fMRI) and event-related potentials (ERP) have been studied for possible application to index deception.
Past studies have shown evidences that strongly supporting the hypothesis that deception requires the coordination of multiple cognitive processes and thus is more cognitively taxing than truth telling.
Despite the positive findings, previous studies were often criticized for not capturing lying as it exists in the real world. Indeed, majority of the experimental paradigms required participants to lie about perceptual
stimuli or memorized materials. More importantly, unlike lying in the real world, the lies generated in research labs were often not spontaneous but instructed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To increase the translational value of the research in deception and lie detection, we aim to investigate the neural correlates of lying using paradigms that can elicit lying similar to those in the real world.
In addition, we also seek to explore the structure of dispositional deception by developing and validating a short and reliable questionnaire to characterize individuals&amp;rsquo; lying patterns.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indices of effect existence and significance in the Bayesian framework</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2019_bayesian/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2019_bayesian/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
