<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Why Join Us | The Clinical Brain Lab</title>
    <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/join/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/join/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Why Join Us</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/images/icon_hu30d0ad82a56c1708370149d7b9443316_148842_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Why Join Us</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/join/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part-time Student Assistant Position at The Clinical Brain Lab</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/join/join_cbl_part-time-ra/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/join/join_cbl_part-time-ra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #FFFF00&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Now Open for Applications&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Clinical Brain Lab, led by Principal Investigator Prof. Annabel Chen, is looking to hire 3 part-time undergraduate research assistants (10 hours/week) to assist with the recruitment and data collection of two neuroimaging studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will be part of a dynamic team of researchers who are using cutting-edge functional near-infrared spectroscopy (fNIRS) and magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) to investigate the brain and behaviour of adults and children when presented with different Singaporean cultural stimuli.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;job-scope&#34;&gt;Job Scope&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depending on your goals for joining us, you will be involved in some of the following activities:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Administrative support for recruitment and screening of participants&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assist with data collection using fNIRS and MRI equipment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assist with contacting participants and collating questionnaire responses&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data preprocessing of MRI and fNIRS datasets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other activities that support the research studies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;requirements&#34;&gt;Requirements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You must be a current undergraduate student at Nanyang Technological University (NTU)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fast learner and eager to acquire advanced neuroimaging data collection skills&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ability to work on some weekends (for data collection)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Previous experience in neuroimaging research is an advantage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;apply&#34;&gt;Apply&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in this job opening, please contact:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Principal Investigator: Prof. Annabel Chen Shen-Hsing
Tel: +65 6908 1457
Email:annabelchen@ntu.edu.sg&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research Fellow: Dr. Atiqah Azhari
Email:nuratiqah.azhari@ntu.edu.sg&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Assistant Position at The Clinical Brain Lab</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/join/join_cbl_research-assistant/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/join/join_cbl_research-assistant/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #FFFF00&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Now Open for Applications&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Clinical Brain Laboratory within the School of Social Sciences seeks applications for the position of Research Assistant. The Research Assistant will be an integral member of an inter-disciplinary research lab developing multimodal methodologies for non-invasive brain stimulation and neurophysiology to measure neural adaptations to cognitive-motor training intervention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The successful candidate will be responsible for overseeing the day-to-day operations of research projects. This position requires task-orientation, excellent organizational skills, attention to details and accuracy, flexibility in responding to fluid situations, good interpersonal skills, as well as the ability to work independently. The main research modalities in our lab include neuropsychological assessments, cognitive tests, functional Magnetic Resonance (fMRI), diffusion MRI (DTI, HARDI, DSI), electroencephalography (EEG), Transcranial Magnetic Stimulation (TMS).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;job-scope&#34;&gt;Job Scope&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Day to day coordination of funded projects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Preparation of ethics documents to institutional review boards.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Participant recruitment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data collection using multimodal neuromodulation and neurophysiological recordings, such as electroencephalography and transcranial magnetic stimulation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Liaise with stakeholders and project collaborators.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Systems administration, including maintenance of network servers and data security.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contribute to the production of research reports.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perform other tasks as required by the Principal Investigators relevant to the research.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;requirements&#34;&gt;Requirements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bachelors (Honours) degree in Psychology, Cognitive Neuroscience or related field from University of good standing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experience with neuromodulation and/or neurophysiological techniques such as; transcranial magnetic stimulation, transcranial direct-current stimulation, electroencephalography and/or functional near-infrared spectroscopy is preferred.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good project coordination and administration skills, including data management and storage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strong oral and written communication skills.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Excellent organizational skills and able to work within given deadlines.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Self-directed learner who effectively picks up relevant skills as needed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;apply&#34;&gt;Apply&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To apply, please send Curriculum Vitae, letter of application with research interests, and three letters of recommendation to 
&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:annabelchen@ntu.edu.sg&#34;&gt;annabelchen@ntu.edu.sg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contact information&lt;/strong&gt;: Professor S.H. Annabel Chen, PhD, Professor, of Psychology, School of Social Sciences, Nanyang Technological University, 48 Nanyang Drive, SHHK-04-19, Singapore 639818, phone +65-6316-8836&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part-time System Administration Position at The Clinical Brain Lab</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/join/join_cbl_system-admin/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/join/join_cbl_system-admin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #FFFF00&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Now Open for Applications&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Clinical Brain Lab housed within the Division of Psychology at NTU is seeking a part-time system administrator to help with setting up and maintaining networked servers used for image analyses within the lab. The main research focus of the lab is studying brain functions using neuroimaging methods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Clinical Brain Lab is currently involved in various projects in neuroimaging and technological applications in education. The  position will allow acquisition of research experience in this field if the applicant has related interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;job-scope&#34;&gt;Job Scope&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an hourly position of 8-10 hours per week (negotiable). The duties of this position include the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evaluate and install software packages on behalf of users.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manage software licenses (E.g. CALs, Matlab etc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ensure QoS and security for servers. (Security design and implementation)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upgrading and patching server operating systems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plan and manage storage life cycle, including backups.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evaluating software for future deployment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Troubleshoot any other software and hardware problems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Website webmaster (GitHub)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Attend Weekly Lab Meetings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Communicate with related IT personnel for network issues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;requirements&#34;&gt;Requirements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Graduate or undergraduate students may apply. The requirements of this position include the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experience with servers and other high availability appliances.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Managing and configuring network services (E.g. VPN, routing, channel bonding etc).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Troubleshooting FlexNET license manager, remote desktop license manager.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Proficiency in RAID and Network file systems (iSCSI LUN, Targets, CIFS)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Knowledge in web services (Apache, MySQL, FTP)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Design and implementation of Hypervisors and virtualization (E.g. ESXI, resource pools, virtual switches)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Matlab, R, C++ and Scripting (Windows PowerShell, or bash/tcsh)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Familiar with Windows 2008 R2, 2012, CentOS environments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;apply&#34;&gt;Apply&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have the suitable qualifications and are interested, please send detailed CV and inquiry to 
&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:annabelchen@ntu.edu.sg&#34;&gt;annabelchen@ntu.edu.sg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contact information&lt;/strong&gt;: Professor S.H. Annabel Chen, PhD, Professor, of Psychology, School of Social Sciences, Nanyang Technological University, 48 Nanyang Drive, SHHK-04-19, Singapore 639818, phone +65-6316-8836&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Opportunities at Centre for Lifelong Learning and Individualised Cognition (CLIC)</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/join/join_clic_postdoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/join/join_clic_postdoc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #FFFF00&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Now Open for Applications&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Centre for Lifelong Learning and Individualised Cognition (CLIC)&lt;/strong&gt;, funded by the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nrf.gov.sg/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;National Research Foundation (NRF)&lt;/a&gt; in Singapore and coordinated through the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.create.edu.sg/about-create/research-centres/cares&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Cambridge Centre for Advanced Research and Education in Singapore (CARES)&lt;/a&gt;, is a collaboration between Nanyang Technological University (NTU) and the University of Cambridge. CLIC is a flagship programme in the Science of Learning to harness advancements in neuroscience to develop &lt;strong&gt;cognitive training programmes&lt;/strong&gt; for the improvement of &lt;strong&gt;lifelong flexible learning&lt;/strong&gt;, focusing initially on adolescents and young adults, but also envisaging work with infants and older adults. This is a strategic global initiative for the Universities of Cambridge and NTU that brings together multidisciplinary expertise from over 30 investigators in the areas of Neuroscience, Psychology, Linguistics and Education across the two universities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ntu.edu.sg/Pages/home.aspx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Nanyang Technological University&lt;/a&gt; is a research intensive university currently ranked 13th globally and placed 1st amongst the world’s best young universities. The University has Colleges of Engineering, Business, Science, Humanities, Arts, &amp;amp; Social Sciences, and an Interdisciplinary Graduate School. Further, the new Lee Kong Chian School of Medicine benefits from a dual campus located at Novena, in close proximity to the Singapore city centre. The Cognitive Neuroimaging Centre (CoNiC) houses state-of-the-art neuroimaging facilities including a newly installed 3T MRI scanner and MEG, as well as new EEG, NIRS, TMS and tDCS equipment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first phase of the CLIC program will initially be housed at Nanyang Technological University, Singapore. As the programme progresses, other sites will be developed to meet the needs of the experimental programme. The new CLIC research centre will provide a vibrant, fast-paced, international and interdisciplinary environment with excellent opportunities for skills development and knowledge exchange between partner Principal Investigator labs in Singapore and Cambridge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Principal Investigators involved in the first phase of the research programme include: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;From Cambridge:&lt;/strong&gt; Director Professor Zoe Kourtzi (Psychology), Senior Scientific Advisor Professor Trevor Robbins (Psychology), Deputy Directors Professor Henriette Hendriks (Linguistics), Professor Anna Vignoles (Education), and Imaging Lead - Professor John Suckling (Psychiatry); supported by co-Investigators Prof Barbara Sahakian (Psychiatry) and Dr Michelle Ellefson (Education).  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;From NTU:&lt;/strong&gt;  Director Professor Annabel Chen (Psychology), Deputy Director Asst Prof Victoria Leong (Psychology), Imaging Lead - Professor Balázs Gulyas (LKCMedicine), and Principal Investigators Professor David Hung (NIE), Asst Prof Bobby Cheon (Psychology) and Assoc Prof Georgios Christopoulos (Nanyang Business School); supported by co-Investigator Dr Teo Chew Lee (NIE). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;list-of-available-positions&#34;&gt;List of Available Positions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;research-fellow-positions&#34;&gt;Research Fellow Positions:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://cradle.ntu.edu.sg/aboutus/Documents/Research%20Fellow_Research%20Engineer%20in%20Neuroimaging%20and%20MRI%20Pulse%20Sequence%20%28RF6%29.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Research Fellow/Research Engineer in Neuroimaging and MRI Pulse Sequence (RF6)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://cradle.ntu.edu.sg/aboutus/Documents/Research%20Fellow%20in%20Neuroimaging%20and%20Cognition%20%28RSB%20RF3%29.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Research Fellow in Neuroimaging and Cognition (RSB RF3)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://cradle.ntu.edu.sg/aboutus/Documents/Research%20Fellow%20in%20Neuroimaging%20and%20Intervention%20%28RSB%20RF4%29.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Research Fellow in Neuroimaging and Intervention (RSB RF4)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;research-assistantassociate-positions&#34;&gt;Research Assistant/Associate Positions:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://cradle.ntu.edu.sg/aboutus/Documents/Research%20Assistant_Associate%20%28RA10-12%29.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Cognition &amp;amp; Neuroimaging (RA10-12)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more available positions at CLIC, please kindly visit this link: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://cradle.ntu.edu.sg/aboutus/Pages/Centre-for-Lifelong-Learning-and-Individualised-Cognition-%28CLIC%29.aspx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Centre for Lifelong Learning and Individualised Cognition (CLIC)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhD fellowships</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/join/join_cbl_phd2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/join/join_cbl_phd2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #FFFF00&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Now Open for Applications&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are currently actively recruiting for PhD students interested in developing research in educational neuroscience, affective neuroscience and aging neuroscience (specifically in older neurological patients).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;job-scope&#34;&gt;Job Scope&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research in the lab is focused on the neural basis of higher cognition in the cerebellum, cognitive training in healthy aging and we will be developing an area in Educational Neuroscience. Main research modalities in our lab include: neuropsychological assessments, cognitive tests, functional Magnetic Resonance (fMRI), diffusion MRI (DTI, HARDI, DSI), EEG and Transcranial Magnetic Stimulation (TMS). The candidate will be expected to conduct research in areas noted above, especially using diffusion MRI. However, he/she is also encouraged to develop own related research topic of interest. For more information about the lab please click 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://portal.hss.ntu.edu.sg/annalab/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;looking-for&#34;&gt;Looking For&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We welcome applicants with a &lt;strong&gt;Bachelors&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;Masters degree&lt;/strong&gt; in various backgrounds such as: &lt;strong&gt;experimental psychology, biopsychology, cognitive psychology, neuropsychology, neurology, psychiatry, cognitive neuroscience, electrical engineering, medical engineering, computer science&lt;/strong&gt;, and related fields.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The successful applicant will be enrolled in the graduate psychology program by research. For non-local degree holders, GRE exams (general and subject) will be required for application. Find out more about the 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://psychology.hss.ntu.edu.sg/Programmes/Graduate/Pages/DoctorofPhilosophy.aspx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Graduate Program&lt;/a&gt; and its 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://admissions.ntu.edu.sg/graduate/R-Programs/Pages/default.aspx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Online Application&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;apply&#34;&gt;Apply&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please address questions or send Curriculum Vita to 
&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:annabelchen@ntu.edu.sg&#34;&gt;annabelchen@ntu.edu.sg&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Fellow Position in Science of Learning</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/join/join_cbl_postdoc2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/join/join_cbl_postdoc2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #FFFF00&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Now Open for Applications&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are currently seeking highly motivated individuals who share our passion in deciphering the enigma of the brain to join us at the Clinical Brain Lab , Nanyang Technological University! We are seeking candidates interested in educational neuroscience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;job-scope&#34;&gt;Job Scope&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are interested in building capacity for research in the &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Science of Learning&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, in particular in the area of educational neuroscience. We seek to understand how cognitive neuroscience can be applied to education to optimize learning. The successful candidate will work closely with researchers at the Centre for Research and Development in Learning (
&lt;a href=&#34;https://cradle.ntu.edu.sg/Pages/home.aspx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CRADLE&lt;/a&gt;), National Institute of Education (
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nie.edu.sg/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;NIE&lt;/a&gt;), and other international collaborators from institutes such as Johns Hopkins University, Massachusetts Institute of Technology and/or University of Cambridge. The &lt;strong&gt;current project will be investigating reading brain networks in bilingual children&lt;/strong&gt;. Singapore is a multicultural city that has a conducive education system to study this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main research modalities in our lab include: neuropsychological assessments, cognitive tests, functional Magnetic Resonance (fMRI), diffusion MRI (DTI, HARDI, DSI), electroencephalography (EEG), Transcranial Magnetic Stimulation (TMS).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;looking-for&#34;&gt;Looking For&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We welcome applicants with a &lt;strong&gt;doctorate (PhD)&lt;/strong&gt; degree in various backgrounds such as:
&lt;strong&gt;experimental psychology, biopsychology, cognitive psychology, neuropsychology, neurology,
psychiatry, cognitive neuroscience, electrical engineering, medical engineering, computer science&lt;/strong&gt;, and related fields.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;requirements&#34;&gt;Requirements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Candidates are expected to have good interpersonal skills and to have demonstrated record of excellent scientific writing skills. Desirable qualification includes one or more of the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experience with conducting behavioral experiments in neuropsychology or cognitive psychology.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experience with neuroimaging techniques (MRI/EEG/or TMS).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Familiarity with image data analysis tools such as SPM, FSL, AFNI, DSIStudio, Matlab, Python etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;apply&#34;&gt;Apply&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To apply, please use the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ntu.wd3.myworkdayjobs.com/Careers/job/NTU-Main-Campus-Singapore/Research-Fellow--Psychology-Cognitive-Neuroscience-Education-Science-of-Learning-_R00009385-1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Workday platform&lt;/a&gt; or send Curriculum Vitae, letter of application with research interests, and three letters of recommendation to 
&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:annabelchen@ntu.edu.sg&#34;&gt;annabelchen@ntu.edu.sg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contact information&lt;/strong&gt;: Professor S.H. Annabel Chen, PhD, Professor, of Psychology, School of Social Sciences, Nanyang Technological University, 48 Nanyang Drive, SHHK-04-19, Singapore 639818, phone +65-6316-8836&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
