<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Why Join Us | The Clinical Brain Lab</title>
    <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/join/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/join/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Why Join Us</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/images/icon_hu30d0ad82a56c1708370149d7b9443316_148842_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Why Join Us</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/join/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Assistant Position at the Clinical Brain Lab</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/join/join_cbl_proof_ra/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/join/join_cbl_proof_ra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #FFFF00&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Now Open for Applications&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Clinical Brain Lab within the School of Social Sciences is seeking applications for the position of Research Assistant. The Research Assistant will be an integral member of an inter-disciplinary research lab developing and carrying out neuroimaging methodologies to investigate the neurocognitive processes underlying the belief of deceptive information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The successful candidate will be responsible for overseeing the day-to-day operations of research projects. This position requires task-orientation, excellent organizational skills, attention to details and accuracy, flexibility in responding to fluid situations, good interpersonal skills, as well as the ability to work independently. The main research modalities in our lab include neuropsychological assessments, cognitive tests, functional Magnetic Resonance (fMRI), diffusion MRI (DTI, HARDI, DSI), electroencephalography (EEG), Transcranial Magnetic Stimulation (TMS).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;job-scope&#34;&gt;Job Scope&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Day to day coordination of funded projects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Preparation of ethics documents to institutional review boards.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Participant recruitment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data collection using neurophysiological recordings, such as electroencephalography.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Liaise with stakeholders and project collaborators.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Systems administration, including maintenance of network servers and data security.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contribute to the production of research reports.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perform other tasks as required by the Principal Investigators relevant to the research.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;requirements&#34;&gt;Requirements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bachelors (Honours) degree in Psychology, Cognitive Neuroscience or related field from University of good standing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experience with electroencephalography is preferred.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good project coordination and administration skills, including data management and storage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strong oral and written communication skills.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Excellent organizational skills and able to work within given deadlines.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Self-directed learner who effectively picks up relevant skills as needed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;apply&#34;&gt;Apply&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in this job opening, please contact:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Principal Investigator: Prof. Annabel Chen&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Email: 
&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:AnnabelChen@ntu.edu.sg&#34;&gt;AnnabelChen@ntu.edu.sg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part-time Student Assistant Position at CRADLE</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/join/join_cbl_part-time-ra/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/join/join_cbl_part-time-ra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #FFFF00&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Now Open for Applications&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Centre for Research and Development in Learning (CRADLE), led by Principal Investigator Prof. Annabel Chen, is looking to hire several part-time undergraduate research assistants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will be part of a dynamic team of researchers who apply multi-modal approaches, including neurocognitive assessments, and neuroimaging techniques such as magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) and functional near-infrared spectroscopy (fNIRS) to investigate the neurocognitive mechanisms of literacy and numeracy development in young children.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;job-scope&#34;&gt;Job Scope&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depending on the study you are assisting in, you might be involved in some of the following activities:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assist with participant recruitment and eligibility screening&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assist with behavioural, fNIRS and/or MRI data collection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assist with data coding, maintenance and preprocessing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assist with the translation of research documents&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other activities that support the research studies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;requirements&#34;&gt;Requirements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You must be a current undergraduate student at Nanyang Technological University (NTU)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A self-directed learner who is eager to learn about advanced neuroimaging research&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prior experience or have interests in working with young children&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ability to work on some weekends (for data collection)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Previous experience in neurocognitive or neuroimaging research is an advantage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ability to help with translations (i.e. Mandarin, Malay or Tamil) is an advantage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;apply&#34;&gt;Apply&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in this job opening, please contact:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research Fellow: Dr. Lynette Looi&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Email: 
&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:lynette.looi@ntu.edu.sg&#34;&gt;lynette.looi@ntu.edu.sg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;flyer&#34;&gt;Flyer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/join/BrainNORM.png&#34; alt=&#34;png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhD fellowships</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/join/join_cbl_phd2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/join/join_cbl_phd2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #FFFF00&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Now Open for Applications&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are currently actively recruiting for PhD students interested in developing research in educational neuroscience, affective neuroscience and aging neuroscience (specifically in older neurological patients).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;job-scope&#34;&gt;Job Scope&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research in the lab is focused on the neural basis of higher cognition in the cerebellum, cognitive training in healthy aging and we will be developing an area in Educational Neuroscience. Main research modalities in our lab include: neuropsychological assessments, cognitive tests, functional Magnetic Resonance (fMRI), diffusion MRI (DTI, HARDI, DSI), EEG and Transcranial Magnetic Stimulation (TMS). The candidate will be expected to conduct research in areas noted above, especially using diffusion MRI. However, he/she is also encouraged to develop own related research topic of interest. For more information about the lab please click 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://portal.hss.ntu.edu.sg/annalab/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;looking-for&#34;&gt;Looking For&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We welcome applicants with a &lt;strong&gt;Bachelors&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;Masters degree&lt;/strong&gt; in various backgrounds such as: &lt;strong&gt;experimental psychology, biopsychology, cognitive psychology, neuropsychology, neurology, psychiatry, cognitive neuroscience, electrical engineering, medical engineering, computer science&lt;/strong&gt;, and related fields.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The successful applicant will be enrolled in the graduate psychology program by research. Competitive scholarships may be applied through the Graduate Psychology Program or the Interdisciplinary Graduate Program with CRADLE@NTU (CRADLE-IGP). For non-local degree holders, GRE exams (general and subject) will be required for application. Find out more about the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ntu.edu.sg/education/graduate-programme/ph.d.-in-psychology&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Graduate Psychology Program&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ntu.edu.sg/cradle/home/interdisciplinary-graduate-programme-%28igp%29&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GRADLE-IGP&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;apply&#34;&gt;Apply&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please address questions or send Curriculum Vita to 
&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:annabelchen@ntu.edu.sg&#34;&gt;annabelchen@ntu.edu.sg&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
