<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Why Join Us | The Clinical Brain Lab</title>
    <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/join/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/join/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Why Join Us</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/images/icon_hu30d0ad82a56c1708370149d7b9443316_148842_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Why Join Us</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/join/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Assistant/Associate [3 Full-Time Positions]</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/join/join_clic_ra2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/join/join_clic_ra2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #FFFF00&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Still Open for Applications&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Centre for Lifelong Learning and Individualised Cognition (CLIC)&lt;/strong&gt;, funded by the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nrf.gov.sg/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;National Research Foundation (NRF)&lt;/a&gt; in Singapore and coordinated through the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.create.edu.sg/about-create/research-centres/cares&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Cambridge Centre for Advanced Research and Education in Singapore (CARES)&lt;/a&gt;, is a collaboration between Nanyang Technological University (NTU) and the University of Cambridge. CLIC is a flagship programme in the Science of Learning to harness advancements in neuroscience to develop &lt;strong&gt;cognitive training programmes&lt;/strong&gt; for the improvement of &lt;strong&gt;lifelong flexible learning&lt;/strong&gt;, focusing initially on adolescents and young adults, but also envisaging work with infants and older adults. This is a strategic global initiative for the Universities of Cambridge and NTU that brings together multidisciplinary expertise from over 30 investigators in the areas of Neuroscience, Psychology, Linguistics and Education across the two universities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ntu.edu.sg/Pages/home.aspx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Nanyang Technological University&lt;/a&gt; is a research intensive university currently ranked 13th globally and placed 1st amongst the world’s best young universities. The University has Colleges of Engineering, Business, Science, Humanities, Arts, &amp;amp; Social Sciences, and an Interdisciplinary Graduate School. Further, the new Lee Kong Chian School of Medicine benefits from a dual campus located at Novena, in close proximity to the Singapore city centre. The Cognitive Neuroimaging Centre (CoNiC) houses state-of-the-art neuroimaging facilities including a newly installed 3T MRI scanner and MEG, as well as new EEG, NIRS, TMS and tDCS equipment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first phase of the CLIC program will initially be housed at Nanyang Technological University, Singapore. As the programme progresses, other sites will be developed to meet the needs of the experimental programme. The new CLIC research centre will provide a vibrant, fast-paced, international and interdisciplinary environment with excellent opportunities for skills development and knowledge exchange between partner Principal Investigator labs in Singapore and Cambridge.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Principal Investigators involved in the first phase of the research programme include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;From Cambridge:&lt;/strong&gt; Director Professor Zoe Kourtzi (Psychology), Senior Scientific Advisor Professor Trevor Robbins (Psychology), Deputy Directors Professor Henriette Hendriks (Linguistics), Professor Anna Vignoles (Education), and Imaging Lead - Professor John Suckling (Psychiatry); supported by co-Investigators Prof Barbara Sahakian (Psychiatry) and Dr Michelle Ellefson (Education). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;From NTU:&lt;/strong&gt;  Director Professor Annabel Chen (Psychology), Deputy Director Asst Prof Victoria Leong (Psychology), Imaging Lead - Professor Balázs Gulyas (LKCMedicine), and Principal Investigators Professor David Hung (NIE), Asst Prof Bobby Cheon (Psychology) and Assoc Prof George Christopoulos (Nanyang Business School); supported by co-Investigator Teo Chew Lee (NIE).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CLIC program is seeking &lt;strong&gt;three full-time Research Assistants/Associates (RAs)&lt;/strong&gt; for a &lt;strong&gt;two-year term&lt;/strong&gt; (with potential opportunities for reappointment). The RAs will support research activities focusing on cognitive flexibility and learning, and training-related brain changes among adults and adolescents. Given the highly inter-disciplinary nature of the project, the RAs will be expected to take on opportunities for involvement in research activities related to human neuroimaging, language, infant cognition/learning and pedagogy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;job-scope&#34;&gt;Job Scope&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assisting with participant recruitment and participant handling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assisting with cognitive testing of participants&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assisting with setting up brain imaging protocols and collecting neuroimaging data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conducting data coding, data entry, and data analysis of collected datasets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Performing general project administration tasks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conducting literature reviews for publications and research briefings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assisting with preparation for academic publications (e.g., journal, conference, book)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contributing to the production of research reports&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contributing to the dissemination of research findings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Performing other research-related tasks as required by the Principal Investigators&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;looking-for&#34;&gt;Looking For&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;essential-requirements&#34;&gt;Essential Requirements:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bachelor and/or Master&amp;rsquo;s degree in Psychology, Neuropsychology, Cognitive Neuroscience or a related discipline&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prior experience in conducting adult cognitive testing and neuroimaging (fMRI, EEG)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prior experience with participant recruitment processes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prior experience and familiarity with data management protocols and ethical regulatory frameworks in Singapore&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experience in performing general administration tasks for research projects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experience in producing research reports&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good statistical knowledge and skills, including familiarity with statistical analysis software such as R and SPSS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good IT skills (Office®)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strong interpersonal, written and verbal communication skills&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Excellent organizational skills and able to work within given deadlines&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;preferred-skills-and-experience&#34;&gt;Preferred Skills and Experience:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data management experience with REDCap&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prior experience with cognitive training and intervention studies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prior experience with interdisciplinary work and teams&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interest and experience in working with different age groups (e.g. infants and older adults)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prior experience working with Singaporean organizations / businesses&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prior experience with academic publication processes and reports&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Self-directed learner who effectively picks up relevant skills as needed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;apply&#34;&gt;Apply&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To apply, please send &lt;strong&gt;Curriculum Vitae, letter of application with research interests, and three letters of recommendation&lt;/strong&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:CLIC@ntu.edu.sg&#34;&gt;CLIC@ntu.edu.sg&lt;/a&gt;. Please indicate the reference number for this position: &lt;strong&gt;CLIC_RA10-12&lt;/strong&gt; in all application documents and correspondences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contact information:&lt;/strong&gt; Centre for Research and Development in Learning, Nanyang Technological University, Academic Building North, 61 Nanyang Drive, ABN-01b-10, Singapore 637335, Phone +65 6908 1458&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Fellow Position in Multimodal Neuroimaging</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/join/join_clic_postdoc5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/join/join_clic_postdoc5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #FFFF00&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Still Open for Applications&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Centre for Lifelong Learning and Individualised Cognition (CLIC)&lt;/strong&gt;, funded by the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nrf.gov.sg/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;National Research Foundation (NRF)&lt;/a&gt; in Singapore and coordinated through the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.create.edu.sg/about-create/research-centres/cares&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Cambridge Centre for Advanced Research and Education in Singapore (CARES)&lt;/a&gt;, is a collaboration between Nanyang Technological University (NTU) and the University of Cambridge. CLIC is a flagship programme in the Science of Learning to harness advancements in neuroscience to develop &lt;strong&gt;cognitive training programmes&lt;/strong&gt; for the improvement of &lt;strong&gt;lifelong flexible learning&lt;/strong&gt;, focusing initially on adolescents and young adults, but also envisaging work with infants and older adults. This is a strategic global initiative for the Universities of Cambridge and NTU that brings together multidisciplinary expertise from over 30 investigators in the areas of Neuroscience, Psychology, Linguistics and Education across the two universities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new CLIC research centre will be initially housed at Nanyang Technological University, Singapore. It will provide a vibrant, fast-paced, international and interdisciplinary environment with excellent opportunities for skills development and knowledge exchange between partner Principal Investigator labs in Singapore and Cambridge.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Principal Investigators involved in the first phase of the research programme include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;From Cambridge:&lt;/strong&gt; Director Professor Zoe Kourtzi (Psychology), Senior Scientific Advisor Professor Trevor Robbins (Psychology), Deputy Directors Professor Henriette Hendriks (Linguistics), Professor Anna Vignoles (Education), and Imaging Lead - Professor John Suckling (Psychiatry); supported by co-Investigators Prof Barbara Sahakian (Psychiatry) and Dr Michelle Ellefson (Education). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;From NTU:&lt;/strong&gt;  Director Professor Annabel Chen (Psychology), Deputy Director Asst Prof Victoria Leong (Psychology), Imaging Lead - Professor Balázs Gulyas (LKCMedicine), and Principal Investigators Professor David Hung (NIE), Asst Prof Bobby Cheon (Psychology) and Assoc Prof George Christopoulos (Nanyang Business School); supported by co-Investigator Teo Chew Lee (NIE).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CLIC program is seeking &lt;strong&gt;one full-time Research Fellow&lt;/strong&gt; to support research activities on neuroimaging, and training-related brain changes in adults. Given the highly inter-disciplinary nature of the project, the research fellow will be expected to take on opportunities for involvement in research activities related to human neuroimaging, language, infant cognition/learning and pedagogy. We anticipate the successful candidate to perform within a dynamic interdisciplinary research environment working collaboratively with project team members. This position will be focused on neuroimaging data collection and processing, and co-supervised by Professor John Suckling and Professor Balazs Gulyas with input from Professor Annabel Chen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;job-scope&#34;&gt;Job Scope&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Preparation and implementation of MRI pulse sequences&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Development of MRI and EEG data acquisition protocols&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Collection of multimodal neuroimaging data (MRI+EEG)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Computational modelling and analysis of neuroimaging data and behavioural data from cognitive and related tasks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supporting and training of research assistants, graduate and undergraduate students&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conduct analysis of data and integrate research findings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conduct literature reviews for publications and research briefings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Author and co-author academic publications (e.g., journal, conference, book)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contribute to the production of research reports&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contribute to the dissemination of research findings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perform other tasks related to the research as required by the Principal Investigators&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;looking-for&#34;&gt;Looking For&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;essential-requirements&#34;&gt;Essential Requirements:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Post graduate qualification, PhD, or relevant experience&lt;/strong&gt; in &lt;strong&gt;experimental psychology, biopsychology, cognitive psychology, neuropsychology, neurology, psychiatry, cognitive neuroscience, electrical engineering, medical engineering, computer science, and related fields&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experience in working with and implementing MRI pulse sequences, especially MRS sequences&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experience in collection and analysis of multimodal neuroimaging data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Familiarity with image data analysis tools such as SPM, FSL, AFNI, DSIStudio, and programming skills (Matlab, Python etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experience in preparing academic reports and presentations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good statistical knowledge and IT skills (common office software e.g. Microsoft Office)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strong ability to work within a multidisciplinary team&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strong interpersonal, written and verbal communication skills&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Excellent organizational skills and able to work within given deadlines&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;preferred-skills-and-experience&#34;&gt;Preferred Skills and Experience:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Familiarity with neuroimaging techniques (MRI, MRS, EEG) applied to computational neuroscience methods&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experience of data Management with databases (e.g. REDCap, MySQL)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prior experience working with Singaporean organizations / business&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prior experience with academic publication processes and reports&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Self-directed learner who effectively picks up relevant skills as needed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;apply&#34;&gt;Apply&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To apply, please send &lt;strong&gt;Curriculum Vitae, letter of application with research interests, and three letters of recommendation&lt;/strong&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:CLIC@ntu.edu.sg&#34;&gt;CLIC@ntu.edu.sg&lt;/a&gt;. Please indicate the reference number for this position: &lt;strong&gt;CLIC_RF6&lt;/strong&gt; in all application documents and correspondences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contact information:&lt;/strong&gt; Centre for Research and Development in Learning, Nanyang Technological University, Academic Building North, 61 Nanyang Drive, ABN-01b-10, Singapore 637335, Phone +65 6908 1458&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Fellow Position in Neuroimaging Data Analyses</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/join/join_clic_postdoc3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/join/join_clic_postdoc3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #FFFF00&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Still Open for Applications&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Centre for Lifelong Learning and Individualised Cognition (CLIC)&lt;/strong&gt;, funded by the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nrf.gov.sg/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;National Research Foundation (NRF)&lt;/a&gt; in Singapore and coordinated through the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.create.edu.sg/about-create/research-centres/cares&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Cambridge Centre for Advanced Research and Education in Singapore (CARES)&lt;/a&gt;, is a collaboration between Nanyang Technological University (NTU) and the University of Cambridge. CLIC is a flagship programme in the Science of Learning to harness advancements in neuroscience to develop &lt;strong&gt;cognitive training programmes&lt;/strong&gt; for the improvement of &lt;strong&gt;lifelong flexible learning&lt;/strong&gt;, focusing initially on adolescents and young adults, but also envisaging work with infants and older adults. This is a strategic global initiative for the Universities of Cambridge and NTU that brings together multidisciplinary expertise from over 30 investigators in the areas of Neuroscience, Psychology, Linguistics and Education across the two universities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new CLIC research centre will be initially housed at Nanyang Technological University, Singapore. It will provide a vibrant, fast-paced, international and interdisciplinary environment with excellent opportunities for skills development and knowledge exchange between partner Principal Investigator labs in Singapore and Cambridge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Principal Investigators involved in the first phase of the research programme include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;From Cambridge:&lt;/strong&gt; Director Professor Zoe Kourtzi (Psychology), Senior Scientific Advisor Professor Trevor Robbins (Psychology), Deputy Directors Professor Henriette Hendriks (Linguistics), Professor Anna Vignoles (Education), and Imaging Lead - Professor John Suckling (Psychiatry); supported by co-Investigators Prof Barbara Sahakian (Psychiatry) and Dr Michelle Ellefson (Education).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;From NTU:&lt;/strong&gt;  Director Professor Annabel Chen (Psychology), Deputy Director Asst Prof Victoria Leong (Psychology), Imaging Lead - Professor Balázs Gulyas (LKCMedicine), and Principal Investigators Professor David Hung (NIE), Asst Prof Bobby Cheon (Psychology) and Assoc Prof George Christopoulos (Nanyang Business School); supported by co-Investigator Teo Chew Lee (NIE).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CLIC program is seeking &lt;strong&gt;one full-time Research Fellow&lt;/strong&gt; to support research activities on cognitive flexibility and learning, and training-related brain changes among adults and adolescents. Given the highly inter-disciplinary nature of the project, the research fellow will be expected to take on opportunities for involvement in research activities related to human neuroimaging, language, infant cognition/learning and pedagogy. This research position will be focusing on neuroimaging and cognition. We anticipate the successful candidate to perform within a dynamic interdisciplinary research environment and coordinates well with other teams in the CLIC program. This position will be co-supervised by Professor Balazs Gulyas and Professor John Suckling with input from Professor Zoe Kourtzi and Professor Annabel Chen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;job-scope&#34;&gt;Job Scope&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perform computational modelling and analysis of the neuroimaging and behavioural data from cognitive and related domain tasks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Development and implementation of neuroimaging data analyses pipelines&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conduct analysis of data and summarise research findings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Development and implementation of data transfer and curation protocols&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Liaise with other workgroups on data management and multi-modal analyses&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support and training of research assistants, graduate and undergraduate students&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conduct literature reviews for publications and research briefings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Author and co-author academic publications (e.g., journal, conference, book)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contribute to the production of research reports&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contribute to the dissemination of research findings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perform other research-related tasks as required by the Principal Investigators&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;looking-for&#34;&gt;Looking For&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;essential-requirements&#34;&gt;Essential Requirements:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Doctorate (PhD) degree and publication record&lt;/strong&gt; in &lt;strong&gt;experimental psychology, biopsychology, cognitive psychology, neuropsychology, neurology, psychiatry, cognitive neuroscience, electrical engineering, biomedical engineering, computer science, or related fields.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advanced signal processing and programming skills (e.g. with Matlab, Python)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experience with neuroimaging techniques (MRI, EEG and/or TMS).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Familiarity with image data analysis tools such as SPM, FSL, AFNI, and/or DSIStudio, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experience with statistical packages, especially R and SPSS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good statistical knowledge and skills&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good IT skills (i.e., Microsoft Office®)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strong ability to work within a multidisciplinary team&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strong interpersonal, written and verbal communication skills&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Excellent organizational skills and able to work within given deadlines&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;preferred-skills-and-experience&#34;&gt;Preferred Skills and Experience:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experience and/or interest in system administration and network infrastructure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prior experience in analyzing large datasets and data management (e.g. REDCap, MySQL)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prior experience working with Singaporean organizations / business&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prior experience with academic publication processes and reports&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Self-directed learner who effectively picks up relevant skills as needed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;apply&#34;&gt;Apply&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To apply, please send &lt;strong&gt;Curriculum Vitae, letter of application with research interests, and three letters of recommendation&lt;/strong&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:CLIC@ntu.edu.sg&#34;&gt;CLIC@ntu.edu.sg&lt;/a&gt;. Please indicate the reference number for this position: &lt;strong&gt;RSB SG RF3&lt;/strong&gt; in all application documents and correspondences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contact information:&lt;/strong&gt; Centre for Research and Development in Learning, Nanyang Technological University, Academic Building North, 61 Nanyang Drive, ABN-01b-10, Singapore 637335, Phone +65 6908 1458&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Fellow Position in Neuroimaging Study and Cognitive Intervention</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/join/join_clic_postdoc4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/join/join_clic_postdoc4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #FFFF00&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Still Open for Applications&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Centre for Lifelong Learning and Individualised Cognition (CLIC)&lt;/strong&gt;, funded by the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nrf.gov.sg/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;National Research Foundation (NRF)&lt;/a&gt; in Singapore and coordinated through the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.create.edu.sg/about-create/research-centres/cares&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Cambridge Centre for Advanced Research and Education in Singapore (CARES)&lt;/a&gt;, is a collaboration between Nanyang Technological University (NTU) and the University of Cambridge. CLIC is a flagship programme in the Science of Learning to harness advancements in neuroscience to develop &lt;strong&gt;cognitive training programmes&lt;/strong&gt; for the improvement of &lt;strong&gt;lifelong flexible learning&lt;/strong&gt;, focusing initially on adolescents and young adults, but also envisaging work with infants and older adults. This is a strategic global initiative for the Universities of Cambridge and NTU that brings together multidisciplinary expertise from over 30 investigators in the areas of Neuroscience, Psychology, Linguistics and Education across the two universities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new CLIC research centre will be initially housed at Nanyang Technological University, Singapore. It will provide a vibrant, fast-paced, international and interdisciplinary environment with excellent opportunities for skills development and knowledge exchange between partner Principal Investigator labs in Singapore and Cambridge.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Principal Investigators involved in the first phase of the research programme include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;From Cambridge:&lt;/strong&gt; Director Professor Zoe Kourtzi (Psychology), Senior Scientific Advisor Professor Trevor Robbins (Psychology), Deputy Directors Professor Henriette Hendriks (Linguistics), Professor Anna Vignoles (Education), and Imaging Lead - Professor John Suckling (Psychiatry); supported by co-Investigators Prof Barbara Sahakian (Psychiatry) and Dr Michelle Ellefson (Education). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;From NTU:&lt;/strong&gt;  Director Professor Annabel Chen (Psychology), Deputy Director Asst Prof Victoria Leong (Psychology), Imaging Lead - Professor Balázs Gulyas (LKCMedicine), and Principal Investigators Professor David Hung (NIE), Asst Prof Bobby Cheon (Psychology) and Assoc Prof George Christopoulos (Nanyang Business School); supported by co-Investigator Teo Chew Lee (NIE).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CLIC program is seeking &lt;strong&gt;one full-time Research Fellow&lt;/strong&gt; to support research activities focusing on cognitive flexibility and learning, and training-related brain changes among adults and adolescents. Given the highly inter-disciplinary nature of the project, the research fellow will be expected to take on opportunities for involvement in research activities related to human neuroimaging, language, infant cognition/learning and pedagogy. We anticipate the successful candidate to be dynamic and versatile in managing and coordinating team members to conduct the intervention study with adult participants from the university and the community. This position will be co-supervised by Professor Barbara Sahakian and Professor Annabel Chen with input from Asst Prof Victoria Leong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;job-scope&#34;&gt;Job Scope&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Oversee the implementation of the neuroimaging and cognitive flexibility intervention study&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Oversee participant recruitment and logistics with supervision of research assistants, graduate and undergraduate students&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Develop surveys, cognitive and behavioural tasks, and training programmes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integration of neuroimaging and behavioural data to examine effects of the intervention&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conduct analysis of data and summarise research findings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Liaise with other work groups to integrate data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conduct literature reviews for publications and research briefings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assist with preparing academic publications (e.g., journal, conference, book)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contribute to the production of research reports&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contribute to the dissemination of research findings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Performing other research-relevant tasks as required by the Principal Investigators&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;looking-for&#34;&gt;Looking For&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;essential-requirements&#34;&gt;Essential Requirements:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Doctorate (PhD) degree&lt;/strong&gt; in &lt;strong&gt;experimental psychology, biopsychology, cognitive psychology, neuropsychology, neurology, psychiatry, cognitive neuroscience, electrical engineering, medical engineering, computer science, and/or related fields.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experience with conducting behavioral experiments in neuropsychology or cognitive psychology.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experience with neuroimaging techniques (MRI or EEG)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Familiarity with image data analysis tools such as SPM, FSL, AFNI, or DSIStudio, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experience with statistical packages, e.g. R and SPSS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experience in preparing academic reports and presentations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good statistical knowledge and skills&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good IT skills (i.e., Microsoft Office®)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ability to work within a multidisciplinary team with adequate amount of leadership&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strong interpersonal, written and verbal communication skills&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Excellent organizational skills and able to work within given deadlines&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;preferred-skills-and-experience&#34;&gt;Preferred Skills and Experience:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prior experience in conducting, collecting and analysing data for psychological testing, behavioural testing and neuroimaging experiments especially in Singapore&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Basic programing skills (e.g. Matlab, Python etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prior experience in analyzing large datasets and data management (e.g. REDCap, MySQL)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prior experience with interdisciplinary research and teams&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prior experience working with Singaporean organizations / business&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prior experience with academic publication processes and reports&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Self-directed learner who effectively picks up relevant skills as needed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;apply&#34;&gt;Apply&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To apply, please send &lt;strong&gt;Curriculum Vitae, letter of application with research interests, and three letters of recommendation&lt;/strong&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:CLIC@ntu.edu.sg&#34;&gt;CLIC@ntu.edu.sg&lt;/a&gt;. Please indicate the reference number for this position: &lt;strong&gt;RSB SG RF4&lt;/strong&gt; in all application documents and correspondences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contact information:&lt;/strong&gt; Centre for Research and Development in Learning, Nanyang Technological University, Academic Building North, 61 Nanyang Drive, ABN-01b-10, Singapore 637335, Phone +65 6908 1458&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doctorate Research Fellowship</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/join/join_cbl_phd2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/join/join_cbl_phd2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #FFFF00&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Still Open for Applications&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are currently actively recruiting for PhD students interested in developing research in educational neuroscience, affective neuroscience and aging neuroscience (specifically in older neurological patients).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;job-scope&#34;&gt;Job Scope&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research in the lab is focused on the neural basis of higher cognition in the cerebellum, cognitive training in healthy aging and we will be developing an area in Educational Neuroscience. Main research modalities in our lab include: neuropsychological assessments, cognitive tests, functional Magnetic Resonance (fMRI), diffusion MRI (DTI, HARDI, DSI), EEG and Transcranial Magnetic Stimulation (TMS). The candidate will be expected to conduct research in areas noted above, especially using diffusion MRI. However, he/she is also encouraged to develop own related research topic of interest. For more information about the lab please click 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://portal.hss.ntu.edu.sg/annalab/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;looking-for&#34;&gt;Looking For&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We welcome applicants with a &lt;strong&gt;Bachelors&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;Masters degree&lt;/strong&gt; in various backgrounds such as: &lt;strong&gt;experimental psychology, biopsychology, cognitive psychology, neuropsychology, neurology, psychiatry, cognitive neuroscience, electrical engineering, medical engineering, computer science&lt;/strong&gt;, and related fields.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The successful applicant will be enrolled in the graduate psychology program by research. For non-local degree holders, GRE exams (general and subject) will be required for application. Find out more about the 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://psychology.hss.ntu.edu.sg/Programmes/Graduate/Pages/DoctorofPhilosophy.aspx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Graduate Program&lt;/a&gt; and its 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://admissions.ntu.edu.sg/graduate/R-Programs/Pages/default.aspx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Online Application&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;apply&#34;&gt;Apply&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please address questions or send Curriculum Vita to &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:annabelchen@ntu.edu.sg&#34;&gt;annabelchen@ntu.edu.sg&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Fellow Position in Science of Learning</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/join/join_cbl_postdoc2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/join/join_cbl_postdoc2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #FFFF00&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Still Open for Applications&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are currently seeking highly motivated individuals who share our passion in deciphering the enigma of the brain to join us at the Clinical Brain Lab , Nanyang Technological University! We are seeking candidates interested in educational neuroscience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;job-scope&#34;&gt;Job Scope&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are interested in building capacity for research in the &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Science of Learning&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, in particular in the area of educational neuroscience. We seek to understand how cognitive neuroscience can be applied to education to optimize learning. The successful candidate will work closely with researchers at the Centre for Research and Development in Learning (
&lt;a href=&#34;https://cradle.ntu.edu.sg/Pages/home.aspx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CRADLE&lt;/a&gt;), National Institute of Education (
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nie.edu.sg/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;NIE&lt;/a&gt;), and other international collaborators from institutes such as Johns Hopkins University, Massachusetts Institute of Technology and/or University of Cambridge. The &lt;strong&gt;current project will be investigating reading brain networks in bilingual children&lt;/strong&gt;. Singapore is a multicultural city that has a conducive education system to study this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main research modalities in our lab include: neuropsychological assessments, cognitive tests, functional Magnetic Resonance (fMRI), diffusion MRI (DTI, HARDI, DSI), electroencephalography (EEG), Transcranial Magnetic Stimulation (TMS).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;looking-for&#34;&gt;Looking For&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We welcome applicants with a &lt;strong&gt;doctorate (PhD)&lt;/strong&gt; degree in various backgrounds such as:
&lt;strong&gt;experimental psychology, biopsychology, cognitive psychology, neuropsychology, neurology,
psychiatry, cognitive neuroscience, electrical engineering, medical engineering, computer science&lt;/strong&gt;, and related fields.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;requirements&#34;&gt;Requirements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Candidates are expected to have good interpersonal skills and to have demonstrated record of excellent scientific writing skills. Desirable qualification includes one or more of the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experience with conducting behavioral experiments in neuropsychology or cognitive psychology.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experience with neuroimaging techniques (MRI/EEG/or TMS).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Familiarity with image data analysis tools such as SPM, FSL, AFNI, DSIStudio, Matlab, Python etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;apply&#34;&gt;Apply&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To apply, please send Curriculum Vitae, letter of application with research interests, and three letters of recommendation to &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:annabelchen@ntu.edu.sg&#34;&gt;annabelchen@ntu.edu.sg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contact information&lt;/strong&gt;: Professor S.H. Annabel Chen, PhD, Psychology, School of Social Sciences, Nanyang Technological University, 14 Nanyang Drive, HSS‐04‐19, Singapore 637332, phone +65‐6316‐8836.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
