<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Why Join Us | The Clinical Brain Lab</title>
    <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/join/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/join/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Why Join Us</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/images/icon_hu30d0ad82a56c1708370149d7b9443316_148842_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Why Join Us</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/join/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part-time Student Assistant Position at The Clinical Brain Lab</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/join/join_cbl_part-time-ra/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/join/join_cbl_part-time-ra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #FFFF00&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Now Open for Applications&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Clinical Brain Lab, led by Principal Investigator Prof. Annabel Chen, is looking to hire 3 part-time undergraduate research assistants (10 hours/week) to assist with the recruitment and data collection of two neuroimaging studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will be part of a dynamic team of researchers who are using cutting-edge functional near-infrared spectroscopy (fNIRS) and magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) to investigate the brain and behaviour of adults and children when presented with different Singaporean cultural stimuli.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;job-scope&#34;&gt;Job Scope&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depending on your goals for joining us, you will be involved in some of the following activities:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Administrative support for recruitment and screening of participants&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assist with data collection using fNIRS and MRI equipment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assist with contacting participants and collating questionnaire responses&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data preprocessing of MRI and fNIRS datasets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other activities that support the research studies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;requirements&#34;&gt;Requirements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You must be a current undergraduate student at Nanyang Technological University (NTU)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fast learner and eager to acquire advanced neuroimaging data collection skills&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ability to work on some weekends (for data collection)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Previous experience in neuroimaging research is an advantage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;apply&#34;&gt;Apply&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in this job opening, please contact:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Principal Investigator: Prof. Annabel Chen Shen-Hsing
Tel: +65 6908 1457
Email:annabelchen@ntu.edu.sg&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research Fellow: Dr. Atiqah Azhari
Email:nuratiqah.azhari@ntu.edu.sg&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhD fellowships</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/join/join_cbl_phd2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/join/join_cbl_phd2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;background-color: #FFFF00&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Now Open for Applications&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are currently actively recruiting for PhD students interested in developing research in educational neuroscience, affective neuroscience and aging neuroscience (specifically in older neurological patients).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;job-scope&#34;&gt;Job Scope&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research in the lab is focused on the neural basis of higher cognition in the cerebellum, cognitive training in healthy aging and we will be developing an area in Educational Neuroscience. Main research modalities in our lab include: neuropsychological assessments, cognitive tests, functional Magnetic Resonance (fMRI), diffusion MRI (DTI, HARDI, DSI), EEG and Transcranial Magnetic Stimulation (TMS). The candidate will be expected to conduct research in areas noted above, especially using diffusion MRI. However, he/she is also encouraged to develop own related research topic of interest. For more information about the lab please click 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://portal.hss.ntu.edu.sg/annalab/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;looking-for&#34;&gt;Looking For&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We welcome applicants with a &lt;strong&gt;Bachelors&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;Masters degree&lt;/strong&gt; in various backgrounds such as: &lt;strong&gt;experimental psychology, biopsychology, cognitive psychology, neuropsychology, neurology, psychiatry, cognitive neuroscience, electrical engineering, medical engineering, computer science&lt;/strong&gt;, and related fields.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The successful applicant will be enrolled in the graduate psychology program by research. Competitive scholarships may be applied through the Graduate Psychology Program or the Interdisciplinary Graduate Program with CRADLE@NTU (CRADLE-IGP). For non-local degree holders, GRE exams (general and subject) will be required for application. Find out more about the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ntu.edu.sg/education/graduate-programme/ph.d.-in-psychology&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Graduate Psychology Program&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ntu.edu.sg/cradle/home/interdisciplinary-graduate-programme-%28igp%29&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GRADLE-IGP&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;apply&#34;&gt;Apply&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please address questions or send Curriculum Vita to 
&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:annabelchen@ntu.edu.sg&#34;&gt;annabelchen@ntu.edu.sg&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
