<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Teo Jia Li | The Clinical Brain Lab</title>
    <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/author/teo-jia-li/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/author/teo-jia-li/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Teo Jia Li</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/images/icon_hu30d0ad82a56c1708370149d7b9443316_148842_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Teo Jia Li</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/author/teo-jia-li/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Centre for Lifelong Learning and Individualised Cognition</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/clic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/clic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our projects seek to make cognitive neuroscience findings accessible to educators and facilitate collaborative work between educators and researchers.
As technology and globalisation are changing the nature of labour markets and increasing the demand for high levels of skill, the need for individuals to be able to develop new skills during their working careers is becoming increasingly pressing. While there is an increased recognition of the need for flexible behavioural and transferable skills, there is currently a gap in evidence-based training programmes that can effectively support and promote cognitive flexibility across the life course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Centre for Lifelong Learning and Individualised Cognition (CLIC) programme aims to address this gap by developing innovative research in the science of learning and translating it to educational and real-life applications across the life course. We will adopt an integrated interdisciplinary approach that marries cross-disciplinary expertise and methodologies across Cambridge and NTU to target three life periods (early years, adolescence, middle age) when flexible behaviour is critical for coping with highly changing circumstances. Working together, we aspire to provide Singapore with a competitive leading edge in the Science of Learning through its transformative theory, methodological innovation, and high-impact practical outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Ongoing Project:&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Understanding and promoting individual cognitive flexibility – funded by the National Research Foundation, Prime Minister’s Office Singapore under its Campus for Research Excellence and Technological Enterprise (CREATE) programme.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information on the CLIC programme, please visit the official webpage at this link: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cares.cam.ac.uk/research/clic/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CLIC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alumni:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research Fellows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.clinicalbrain.org/author/cheng-xiaoqin/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Cheng Xiao qin, PhD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.clinicalbrain.org/author/elias-ebrahimzadeh/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Elias Ebrahimzadeh, PhD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.clinicalbrain.org/author/chia-lun-liu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Chia-Lun Liu, PhD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.clinicalbrain.org/author/eleanor-koo-wei-shi/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Eleanor Koo Wei Shi, PhD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research Associate:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.clinicalbrain.org/author/hong-min/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Hong Min&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research Assistants:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.clinicalbrain.org/author/tan-jia-yuan-janet/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Janet Tan Jia Yuan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.clinicalbrain.org/author/Marisha-Barth-Ubrani&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Marisha Barth Ubrani&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bilingual Reading Networks</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/reading-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/reading-network/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our projects aim to elucidate the neurocognitive mechanisms underlying typical and impaired reading in bilinguals.
We use a combination of behavioural assessment and neuroimaging techniques to investigate the neural reading networks for bilingual readers from a variety of language profiles, across early childhood and adulthood.
Our projects will shed light on the impact of critical factors (e.g., orthographic depth of scripts, auditory perception skills) on the bilingual reading networks. Our findings will provide implications for neuroscience-informed remediation of reading difficulties for bilingual readers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Completed Projects:&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Effective Biliteracy: The Impact of Script Sets on Bilingual Reading Networks for Typical and Atypical Readers - &lt;em&gt;funded by NTU-JHU Collaborative Grant&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Modulating Reading Networks -&lt;em&gt;funded by NTU-JHU Collaborative Grant&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cognitive Science of Multilingualism In Children (COSMIC) - &lt;em&gt;funded by National Research Foundation&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Research Output:&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Publication:&lt;/b&gt; 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.clinicalbrain.org/publication/2020_learning-biliteracy-tdcs/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Reading proficiency influences the effects of transcranial direct current simulation: Evidence from selective modulation of dorsal and ventral pathways of reading in bilinguals&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Publication:&lt;/b&gt; 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.clinicalbrain.org/publication/2020_tdcs-montages-simulation/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Simulation analyses of tDCS montages for the investigation of dorsal and ventral pathways&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Conference Poster:&lt;/b&gt; Scripts of Mother Tongues Affect Cortical Structure in Bilinguals&amp;rsquo; Reading Network&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Conference Poster:&lt;/b&gt; The Impact of Script Sets on the Functional Organization of Bilinguals&amp;rsquo; Reading Network&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Conference Poster:&lt;/b&gt; Cortical structures in the reading network correlate with reading proficiency in early bilinguals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Conference Poster:&lt;/b&gt; Could tDCS Modulate Bilingual Reading?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
