<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Darren-Yeo | The Clinical Brain Lab</title>
    <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/author/darren-yeo/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/author/darren-yeo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Darren-Yeo</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/images/icon_hu30d0ad82a56c1708370149d7b9443316_148842_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Darren-Yeo</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/author/darren-yeo/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Brain Networks of Reading and Math</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/brain-norm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/brain-norm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tapping on the advancements of neuroimaging, the project aims to develop a combination of behavioural measures that may be as sensitive as neuroimaging measures to delineate the different learning disabilities subgroups in young children. There is a growing prevalence of learning disabilities (LD) in Reading Difficulties (RD), Math Difficulties (MD) and their comorbidity (Reading-Math Difficulties; RMD) in young children. Given the important roles math and reading play in the development of emerging skills during early school years, early identification is crucial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using advanced neuroimaging methods, we aim to better understand the extent to which reading, math and working memory are subserved by common neural substrates at the individual level. We will then further examine these networks in combination with learning disabilities screeners, which will help to distinguish children with RD, MD and RMD at the neural level. We aim to then identify existing sensitive screening tools to delineate the LD subgroups, which will allow prediction to intervention responsiveness, and enable better tailoring of the intervention these young children will receive from the onset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Ongoing Projects:&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Project 1:&lt;/b&gt; Cognitive Screen and Characterization of Reading and Math Skills&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Project 2:&lt;/b&gt; Differentiating the Brain Networks underpinning Reading and Math (Structural MRI, Diffusion MRI, Resting-state Functional MRI, Task-based Functional MRI)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Project 3:&lt;/b&gt; Examining the functional brain networks supporting reading using fNIRS&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Project 4:&lt;/b&gt; Examining the functional brain networks supporting math using fNIRS&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Project 5:&lt;/b&gt; Learning Support in Action&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
