<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | The Clinical Brain Lab</title>
    <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/images/icon_hu30d0ad82a56c1708370149d7b9443316_148842_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perception of Real vs. Fake Information</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/fake-news/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/fake-news/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Deception, or in other words, information that does not reflect reality, created or delivered with the intention of duping the receiver, is increasingly prevalent in the age of social media. With virtual reality, augmented reality, uncontrolled mass communication, and new forms of fiction, it becomes increasingly difficult to separate truth from deception. Moreover, brain mechanisms and other physiological correlates underlying the processing and acceptance of deceptive information remain largely unknown. This study will be a critical first step in understanding how deceitful information becomes endorsed by individuals susceptible to fake news beliefs and conspiracy theories, consequently facilitating counteract measures in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first aim of this study is to establish and validate a strong experimental paradigm for investigating the neurocognitive processes underlying the belief in deceptive (i.e., Fake/Real) information. It should be noted that real and fake in this study is defined by the factual accuracy of the information based on current credible news. The second aim is to investigate how these processes can be experimentally modulated and the extent of their impact on one&amp;rsquo;s deception appraisal. This paradigm will then help to build a computational model of reality belief which in turn will be used to predict the effect of specific interventions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving Cognition through Dance in Older Filipinos with MCI</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/indak/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/indak/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The project aims to provide scientific evidence on a public health intervention that is contextualized in a community setting to reduce dementia risk among older adults with MCI. This is a cluster-randomized, two-arm, single-blind trial of a multicomponent intervention that combines dance called INDAK (Improving Neurocognition through Dance and Kinesthetics), nutrition counseling, and vascular risk management. The intervention group received 12-16 months of dance sessions and vascular management while the control group (CON) received only the vascular management.
The primary outcome is cognitive performance assessed by several behavioral tasks. Secondary outcomes are functional connectivity assessed through brain imaging, and measures of behavioral, functional level, and quality of life. This model can be an ecological, low-cost, and effective program, thereby conducive to widespread implementation in the Philippines as well as in other low-resource settings with similar public health challenges.
This project is a collaboration with St. Luke&amp;rsquo;s Medical Center, Institute for Neurosciences, Quezon City, Philippines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ongoing projects:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/34557142/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;FINOMAIN: FIlipiNO Dance Intervention to MAINtain Cognitive Performance in High Risk Population&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cerebellum &amp; Language</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/cerebellum-language/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/cerebellum-language/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cerebellum has increasingly been recognized for its contributions beyond motor control to higher cognitive functions. Our work focuses on the roles of cerebellum in language. We use neuroimaging techniques to examine the cerebellar involvement and the cerebro-cerebellar contributions towards language and reading-related processes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The findings highlight the role of the cerebellum in reading networks. The implications underscore the need for further research on heterogeneity of cerebellar functions and cerebro-cerebellar functional connectivity to develop a comprehensive understanding of the neural correlates of reading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research Output:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mapping the Cerebellum to the Neural Network of Reading in Bilinguals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Centre for Lifelong Learning and Individualised Cognition</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/clic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/clic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our projects seek to make cognitive neuroscience findings accessible to educators and facilitate collaborative work between educators and researchers.
As technology and globalisation are changing the nature of labour markets and increasing the demand for high levels of skill, the need for individuals to be able to develop new skills during their working careers is becoming increasingly pressing. While there is an increased recognition of the need for flexible behavioural and transferable skills, there is currently a gap in evidence-based training programmes that can effectively support and promote cognitive flexibility across the life course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Centre for Lifelong Learning and Individualised Cognition (CLIC) programme aims to address this gap by developing innovative research in the science of learning and translating it to educational and real-life applications across the life course. We will adopt an integrated interdisciplinary approach that marries cross-disciplinary expertise and methodologies across Cambridge and NTU to target three life periods (early years, adolescence, middle age) when flexible behaviour is critical for coping with highly changing circumstances. Working together, we aspire to provide Singapore with a competitive leading edge in the Science of Learning through its transformative theory, methodological innovation, and high-impact practical outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ongoing Project:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Understanding and promoting individual cognitive flexibility – funded by National Research Foundation, Prime Minister’s Office Singapore under its Campus for Research Excellence and Technological Enterprise (CREATE) programme.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information on the CLIC programme, please visit the official webpage at this link: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cares.cam.ac.uk/research/clic/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CLIC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Active Aging Lifestyle</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/ageing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/ageing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Combining both cognitive and exercise training in an intervention program may be advantageous to enhance cognitive and physical functions.
However, this approach has yet to be well researched and implemented. Given the hot and humid climate and community environments (e.g., sidewalks and street traffic) in Singapore, common aerobic exercises such as walking and jogging may not be the first choice for sedentary older adults in Singapore.
Therefore, we proposed and developed an intervention program (&lt;strong&gt;ExCITE: Exercise-Cognition Integrated Training for Enhancement&lt;/strong&gt;) that incorporates both cognitive and physical exercise components that can be easily implemented and weaved into the lifestyles of our aging population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research Output:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1186/s13102-021-00309-w&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Publication: Acute effects of Square Stepping Exercise on cognitive and social functions in sedentary young adults: A home-based online trial.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.15294/ajpesh.v2i2.62184&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Publication: Short-term effects of Square Stepping Exercise on cognitive and social functions in sedentary older adults: A home-based online trial.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.clinicalbrain.org/publication/2023_tmseeg-youngold/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Poster: Theta-burst stimulation-induced cortical plasticity in younger and older adults: a TMS-EEG study&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.clinicalbrain.org/publication/2023_hrv-affective/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Poster: Associations between brain structure, HRV, and depression and anxiety in a non-clinical sample&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.clinicalbrain.org/publication/2023_hrv-cognition/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Poster: HRV mediates the relationship between isthmus cingulate thickness and inhibitory control&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Behavioural and Neural Correlates of Deception</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/deception/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/deception/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Traditional lie detection as used in polygraph test is based on examining one&amp;rsquo;s physiological arousal (measuring skin conductance,
heart rate, and respiration) to infer lying. However, such physiological arousal may merely be reflecting anxiety and fear during a polygraph examination,
rather than lying per se.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As physiological arousal could not be used to accurately infer lying, researchers are urged to further look into the mental processes related to lying.
To date, different neurophysiological signals, including functional magnetic resonance imaging (fMRI) and event-related potentials (ERP) have been studied for possible application to index deception.
Past studies have shown evidences that strongly supporting the hypothesis that deception requires the coordination of multiple cognitive processes and thus is more cognitively taxing than truth telling.
Despite the positive findings, previous studies were often criticized for not capturing lying as it exists in the real world. Indeed, majority of the experimental paradigms required participants to lie about perceptual
stimuli or memorized materials. More importantly, unlike lying in the real world, the lies generated in research labs were often not spontaneous but instructed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To increase the translational value of the research in deception and lie detection, we aim to investigate the neural correlates of lying using paradigms that can elicit lying similar to those in the real world.
In addition, we also seek to explore the structure of dispositional deception by developing and validating a short and reliable questionnaire to characterize individuals&amp;rsquo; lying patterns.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bilingual Reading Networks</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/reading-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/reading-network/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our projects aim to elucidate the neurocognitive mechanisms underlying typical and impaired reading in bilinguals.
We use a combination of behavioural assessment and neuroimaging techniques to investigate the neural reading networks for bilingual readers from a variety of language profiles, across early childhood and adulthood.
Our projects will shed light on the impact of critical factors (e.g., orthographic depth of scripts, auditory perception skills) on the bilingual reading networks. Our findings will provide implications for neuroscience-informed remediation of reading difficulties for bilingual readers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Completed projects:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Effective Biliteracy: The Impact of Script Sets on Bilingual Reading Networks for Typical and Atypical Readers - &lt;em&gt;funded by NTU-JHU Collaborative Grant&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Modulating Reading Networks -&lt;em&gt;funded by NTU-JHU Collaborative Grant&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cognitive Science of Multilingualism In Children (COSMIC) - &lt;em&gt;funded by National Research Foundation&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Promoting Effective Biliteracy</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/pebbles/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/pebbles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The project aims to develop an early screening and training programme to promote balanced bilingual development and biliteracy attainment in early childhood.
Using a multimodal approach, we will identify early neural, cognitive, and environmental predictors in preschool years for later bilingual and biliteracy development.
We will evaluate the neurocognitive effects of different training programmes on enhancing biliteracy development. The knowledge gained from the project will broaden our understanding of the neurocognitive development of language and reading networks in young bilinguals.
The findings will have significant implications for early screening and effective training for promoting balanced bilingual and biliteracy development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ongoing project:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Promoting Effective Biliteracy in Early Childhood: A Systematic Screening and Training Programme for Balanced Bilingual Development - &lt;em&gt;funded by Singapore Millennium Foundation&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Translating neuroscience for educators</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/translate-neuro/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/translate-neuro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our projects seek to make cognitive neuroscience findings accessible to educators and facilitate collaborative work between educators and researchers.
The broad goals of our research are to encourage and strengthen dialogue between researchers, practitioners and the wider community to consolidate existing knowledge and generate new hypotheses to answer real-world questions in education and learning.
To achieve these goals we utilise a range of approaches, including language translations, open database platforms, meta-analyses and meta-analytic brain connectivity modelling, data-visualisation and focus group discussions.
This work has important implications in developing educator’s brain literacy and informing teaching and learning to support the growing population of diverse child and adult learners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ongoing Project:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Understanding functional relationships between socio-affective and neurocognitive brain networks in adults with ASD and ADHD to better inform learning for learners and educators: Towards maximising the adult learning potential&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developing educator’s Brain Literacy: BrainMap for Teacher Professional Development (DEV 01/21 AMG) (Funded by MOE-ERFP)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Completed Project:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nie.edu.sg/research/projects/project/afd-07-16-zw&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Developing a translating educational neuroscience clearinghouse (TENC) for the differentiated instruction of diverse learners&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Higher Cognition &amp; the Cerebellum</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/cerebellum/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/cerebellum/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cerebellum has increasingly been recognized for its contributions beyond motor control to higher cognitive functions. Our work focuses on the roles of cerebellum in working memory, i.e., the ability to hold information in short-term memory. We use neuroimaging techniques to examine the structural and functional connectivity of the cerebro-cerebellar pathways for verbal and visual working memory.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
