<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | The Clinical Brain Lab</title>
    <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/images/icon_hu30d0ad82a56c1708370149d7b9443316_148842_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Behevioural and Neural Correlates of Deception</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/deception/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/deception/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Traditional lie detection as used in polygraph test is based on examining one&amp;rsquo;s physiological arousal (measuring skin conductance,
heart rate, and respiration) to infer lying. However, such physiological arousal may merely be reflecting anxiety and fear during a polygraph examination,
rather than lying per se.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As physiological arousal could not be used to accurately infer lying, researchers are urged to further look into the mental processes related to lying.
To date, different neurophysiological signals, including functional magnetic resonance imaging (fMRI) and event-related potentials (ERP) have been studied for possible application to index deception.
Past studies have shown evidences that strongly supporting the hypothesis that deception requires the coordination of multiple cognitive processes and thus is more cognitively taxing than truth telling.
Despite the positive findings, previous studies were often criticized for not capturing lying as it exists in the real world. Indeed, majority of the experimental paradigms required participants to lie about perceptual
stimuli or memorized materials. More importantly, unlike lying in the real world, the lies generated in research labs were often not spontaneous but instructed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To increase the translational value of the research in deception and lie detection, we aim to investigate the neural correlates of lying using paradigms that can elicit lying similar to those in the real world.
In addition, we also seek to explore the structure of dispositional deception by developing and validating a short and reliable questionnaire to characterize individuals&#39; lying patterns.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biliteracy</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/biliteracy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/biliteracy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We use a combination of behavioural assessment, neuroimaging techniques, and intervention to investigate the neural reading networks for bilingual readers from a variety of language profiles, across early childhood and adulthood. Our projects aim to identify the critical factors that influence the neurocognitive mechanisms of non-impaired and impaired reading. Our findings will provide implications for neuroscience-informed remediation of reading difficulties to promote effective bilingual and biliteracy development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ongoing projects:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Effective Biliteracy: The Impact of Script Sets on Bilingual Reading Networks for Typical and Atypical Readers (funded by NTU-JHU Collaborative Grant)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Promoting Effective Biliteracy in Early Childhood: A Systematic Screening and Training Programme for Balanced Bilingual Development (funded by Singapore Millennium Foundation)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NRF Reading Brains project? (funded by National Research Foundation)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cerebellum and Cognition</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/cerebellum/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/cerebellum/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Description&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
