<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lin Hsin-Yu | The Clinical Brain Lab</title>
    <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/author/lin-hsin-yu/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/author/lin-hsin-yu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Lin Hsin-Yu</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/images/icon_hu30d0ad82a56c1708370149d7b9443316_148842_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Lin Hsin-Yu</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/author/lin-hsin-yu/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving Cognition through Dance in Older Filipinos with MCI</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/indak/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/indak/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The project aims to provide scientific evidence on a public health intervention that is contextualized in a community setting to reduce dementia risk among older adults with MCI. This is a cluster-randomized, two-arm, single-blind trial of a multicomponent intervention that combines dance called INDAK (Improving Neurocognition through Dance and Kinesthetics), nutrition counseling, and vascular risk management. The intervention group received 12-16 months of dance sessions and vascular management while the control group (CON) received only the vascular management.
The primary outcome is cognitive performance assessed by several behavioral tasks. Secondary outcomes are functional connectivity assessed through brain imaging, and measures of behavioral, functional level, and quality of life. This model can be an ecological, low-cost, and effective program, thereby conducive to widespread implementation in the Philippines as well as in other low-resource settings with similar public health challenges.
This project is a collaboration with St. Luke&amp;rsquo;s Medical Center, Institute for Neurosciences, Quezon City, Philippines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ongoing projects:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/34557142/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;FINOMAIN: FIlipiNO Dance Intervention to MAINtain Cognitive Performance in High Risk Population&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bilingual Reading Networks</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/reading-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/reading-network/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our projects aim to elucidate the neurocognitive mechanisms underlying typical and impaired reading in bilinguals.
We use a combination of behavioural assessment and neuroimaging techniques to investigate the neural reading networks for bilingual readers from a variety of language profiles, across early childhood and adulthood.
Our projects will shed light on the impact of critical factors (e.g., orthographic depth of scripts, auditory perception skills) on the bilingual reading networks. Our findings will provide implications for neuroscience-informed remediation of reading difficulties for bilingual readers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Completed projects:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Effective Biliteracy: The Impact of Script Sets on Bilingual Reading Networks for Typical and Atypical Readers - &lt;em&gt;funded by NTU-JHU Collaborative Grant&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Modulating Reading Networks -&lt;em&gt;funded by NTU-JHU Collaborative Grant&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cognitive Science of Multilingualism In Children (COSMIC) - &lt;em&gt;funded by National Research Foundation&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Promoting Effective Biliteracy</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/pebbles/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/pebbles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The project aims to develop an early screening and training programme to promote balanced bilingual development and biliteracy attainment in early childhood.
Using a multimodal approach, we will identify early neural, cognitive, and environmental predictors in preschool years for later bilingual and biliteracy development.
We will evaluate the neurocognitive effects of different training programmes on enhancing biliteracy development. The knowledge gained from the project will broaden our understanding of the neurocognitive development of language and reading networks in young bilinguals.
The findings will have significant implications for early screening and effective training for promoting balanced bilingual and biliteracy development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ongoing project:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Promoting Effective Biliteracy in Early Childhood: A Systematic Screening and Training Programme for Balanced Bilingual Development - &lt;em&gt;funded by Singapore Millennium Foundation&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
