<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Learning | The Clinical Brain Lab</title>
    <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/tag/learning/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/tag/learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Learning</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/images/icon_hu30d0ad82a56c1708370149d7b9443316_148842_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Learning</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/tag/learning/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bilingual Reading Networks</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/reading-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/reading-network/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our projects aim to elucidate the neurocognitive mechanisms underlying typical and impaired reading in bilinguals.
We use a combination of behavioural assessment and neuroimaging techniques to investigate the neural reading networks for bilingual readers from a variety of language profiles, across early childhood and adulthood.
Our projects will shed light on the impact of critical factors (e.g., orthographic depth of scripts, auditory perception skills) on the bilingual reading networks. Our findings will provide implications for neuroscience-informed remediation of reading difficulties for bilingual readers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ongoing projects:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Effective Biliteracy: The Impact of Script Sets on Bilingual Reading Networks for Typical and Atypical Readers - &lt;em&gt;funded by NTU-JHU Collaborative Grant&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Modulating Reading Networks -&lt;em&gt;funded by NTU-JHU Collaborative Grant&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cognitive Science of Multilingualism In Children (COSMIC) - &lt;em&gt;funded by National Research Foundation&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Promoting Effective Biliteracy</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/pebbles/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/pebbles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The project aims to develop an early screening and training programme to promote balanced bilingual development and biliteracy attainment in early childhood.
Using a multimodal approach, we will identify early neural, cognitive, and environmental predictors in preschool years for later bilingual and biliteracy development.
We will evaluate the neurocognitive effects of different training programmes on enhancing biliteracy development. The knowledge gained from the project will broaden our understanding of the neurocognitive development of language and reading networks in young bilinguals.
The findings will have significant implications for early screening and effective training for promoting balanced bilingual and biliteracy development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ongoing project:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Promoting Effective Biliteracy in Early Childhood: A Systematic Screening and Training Programme for Balanced Bilingual Development - &lt;em&gt;funded by Singapore Millennium Foundation&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Translating neuroscience for educators</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/translate-neuro/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/translate-neuro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our projects seek to make cognitive neuroscience findings accessible to educators and facilitate collaborative work between educators and researchers.
The broad goals of our research are to encourage and strengthen dialogue between researchers, practitioners and the wider community to consolidate existing knowledge and generate new hypotheses to answer real-world questions in education and learning.
To achieve these goals we utilise a range of approaches, including language translations, open database platforms, meta-analyses and meta-analytic brain connectivity modelling, data-visualisation and focus group discussions.
This work has important implications in developing educator’s brain literacy and informing teaching and learning to support the growing population of diverse child and adult learners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ongoing Project:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Understanding functional relationships between socio-affective and neurocognitive brain networks in adults with ASD and ADHD to better inform learning for learners and educators: Towards maximising the adult learning potential&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Completed Project:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nie.edu.sg/research/projects/project/afd-07-16-zw&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Developing a translating educational neuroscience clearinghouse (TENC) for the differentiated instruction of diverse learners&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
