<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Learning | The Clinical Brain Lab</title>
    <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/tag/learning/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/tag/learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Learning</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/images/icon_hu30d0ad82a56c1708370149d7b9443316_148842_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Learning</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/tag/learning/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cognitive and neural mechanisms of learning and interventions for improvement across the adult lifespan: A systematic review protocol</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2024_cog-neural-learning-review-protocol/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2024_cog-neural-learning-review-protocol/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding of Psychological Literacy: Comparative Insights From Undergraduates in China and the United Kingdom</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2024_comparative-psychological-literacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2024_comparative-psychological-literacy/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Subjective versus objective language proficiency measures in the investigation of bilingual effects on cognitive control</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2024_bilingual-cognitive-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2024_bilingual-cognitive-control/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is there a foreign language effect on academic integrity?</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2023_foreignlanguage-integrity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2023_foreignlanguage-integrity/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading and Math in Young Children</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/post/brainnorm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/post/brainnorm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;brainnorm.png&#34; alt=&#34;png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving Cognition through Dance in Older Filipinos with MCI</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/indak/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/indak/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The project aims to provide scientific evidence on a public health intervention that is contextualized in a community setting to reduce dementia risk among older adults with MCI. This is a cluster-randomized, two-arm, single-blind trial of a multicomponent intervention that combines dance called INDAK (Improving Neurocognition through Dance and Kinesthetics), nutrition counseling, and vascular risk management. The intervention group received 12-16 months of dance sessions and vascular management while the control group (CON) received only the vascular management.
The primary outcome is cognitive performance assessed by several behavioral tasks. Secondary outcomes are functional connectivity assessed through brain imaging, and measures of behavioral, functional level, and quality of life. This model can be an ecological, low-cost, and effective program, thereby conducive to widespread implementation in the Philippines as well as in other low-resource settings with similar public health challenges.
This project is a collaboration with St. Luke&amp;rsquo;s Medical Center, Institute for Neurosciences, Quezon City, Philippines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Ongoing Project:&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/34557142/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;FINOMAIN: FIlipiNO Dance Intervention to MAINtain Cognitive Performance in High Risk Population&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Brain Networks of Reading and Math</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/brain-norm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/brain-norm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tapping on the advancements of neuroimaging, the project aims to develop a combination of behavioural measures that may be as sensitive as neuroimaging measures to delineate the different learning disabilities subgroups in young children. There is a growing prevalence of learning disabilities (LD) in Reading Difficulties (RD), Math Difficulties (MD) and their comorbidity (Reading-Math Difficulties; RMD) in young children. Given the important roles math and reading play in the development of emerging skills during early school years, early identification is crucial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using advanced neuroimaging methods, we aim to better understand the extent to which reading, math and working memory are subserved by common neural substrates at the individual level. We will then further examine these networks in combination with learning disabilities screeners, which will help to distinguish children with RD, MD and RMD at the neural level. We aim to then identify existing sensitive screening tools to delineate the LD subgroups, which will allow prediction to intervention responsiveness, and enable better tailoring of the intervention these young children will receive from the onset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Ongoing Projects:&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Project 1:&lt;/b&gt; Cognitive Screen and Characterization of Reading and Math Skills&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Project 2:&lt;/b&gt; Differentiating the Brain Networks underpinning Reading and Math (Structural MRI, Diffusion MRI, Resting-state Functional MRI, Task-based Functional MRI)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Project 3:&lt;/b&gt; Examining the functional brain networks supporting reading using fNIRS&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Project 4:&lt;/b&gt; Examining the functional brain networks supporting math using fNIRS&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Project 5:&lt;/b&gt; Learning Support in Action&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Defining the Science of Learning: A Scoping Review</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2023_science-of-learning_review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2023_science-of-learning_review/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapping the Cerebellum to the Neural Network of Reading in Bilinguals</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2023_ohbm_cerebellum-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2023_ohbm_cerebellum-reading/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading proficiency influences the effects of transcranial direct current stimulation: Evidence from selective modulation of dorsal and ventral pathways of reading in bilinguals</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2020_learning-biliteracy-tdcs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2020_learning-biliteracy-tdcs/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Centre for Lifelong Learning and Individualised Cognition</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/clic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/clic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our projects seek to make cognitive neuroscience findings accessible to educators and facilitate collaborative work between educators and researchers.
As technology and globalisation are changing the nature of labour markets and increasing the demand for high levels of skill, the need for individuals to be able to develop new skills during their working careers is becoming increasingly pressing. While there is an increased recognition of the need for flexible behavioural and transferable skills, there is currently a gap in evidence-based training programmes that can effectively support and promote cognitive flexibility across the life course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Centre for Lifelong Learning and Individualised Cognition (CLIC) programme aims to address this gap by developing innovative research in the science of learning and translating it to educational and real-life applications across the life course. We will adopt an integrated interdisciplinary approach that marries cross-disciplinary expertise and methodologies across Cambridge and NTU to target three life periods (early years, adolescence, middle age) when flexible behaviour is critical for coping with highly changing circumstances. Working together, we aspire to provide Singapore with a competitive leading edge in the Science of Learning through its transformative theory, methodological innovation, and high-impact practical outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Ongoing Project:&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Understanding and promoting individual cognitive flexibility – funded by National Research Foundation, Prime Minister’s Office Singapore under its Campus for Research Excellence and Technological Enterprise (CREATE) programme.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information on the CLIC programme, please visit the official webpage at this link: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cares.cam.ac.uk/research/clic/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CLIC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bilingual Reading Networks</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/reading-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/reading-network/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our projects aim to elucidate the neurocognitive mechanisms underlying typical and impaired reading in bilinguals.
We use a combination of behavioural assessment and neuroimaging techniques to investigate the neural reading networks for bilingual readers from a variety of language profiles, across early childhood and adulthood.
Our projects will shed light on the impact of critical factors (e.g., orthographic depth of scripts, auditory perception skills) on the bilingual reading networks. Our findings will provide implications for neuroscience-informed remediation of reading difficulties for bilingual readers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Completed Projects:&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Effective Biliteracy: The Impact of Script Sets on Bilingual Reading Networks for Typical and Atypical Readers - &lt;em&gt;funded by NTU-JHU Collaborative Grant&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Modulating Reading Networks -&lt;em&gt;funded by NTU-JHU Collaborative Grant&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cognitive Science of Multilingualism In Children (COSMIC) - &lt;em&gt;funded by National Research Foundation&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Research Output:&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Publication:&lt;/b&gt; 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.clinicalbrain.org/publication/2020_learning-biliteracy-tdcs/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Reading proficiency influences the effects of transcranial direct current simulation: Evidence from selective modulation of dorsal and ventral pathways of reading in bilinguals&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Publication:&lt;/b&gt; 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.clinicalbrain.org/publication/2020_tdcs-montages-simulation/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Simulation analyses of tDCS montages for the investigation of dorsal and ventral pathways&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Conference Poster:&lt;/b&gt; Scripts of Mother Tongues Affect Cortical Structure in Bilinguals&amp;rsquo; Reading Network&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Conference Poster:&lt;/b&gt; The Impact of Script Sets on the Functional Organization of Bilinguals&amp;rsquo; Reading Network&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Conference Poster:&lt;/b&gt; Cortical structures in the reading network correlate with reading proficiency in early bilinguals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Conference Poster:&lt;/b&gt; Could tDCS Modulate Bilingual Reading?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Promoting Effective Biliteracy</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/pebbles/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/pebbles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The project aims to develop an early screening and training programme to promote balanced bilingual development and biliteracy attainment in early childhood.
Using a multimodal approach, we will identify early neural, cognitive, and environmental predictors in preschool years for later bilingual and biliteracy development.
We will evaluate the neurocognitive effects of different training programmes on enhancing biliteracy development. The knowledge gained from the project will broaden our understanding of the neurocognitive development of language and reading networks in young bilinguals.
The findings will have significant implications for early screening and effective training for promoting balanced bilingual and biliteracy development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Ongoing Project:&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Promoting Effective Biliteracy in Early Childhood: A Systematic Screening and Training Programme for Balanced Bilingual Development - &lt;em&gt;funded by Singapore Millennium Foundation&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Translating neuroscience for educators</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/translate-neuro/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/translate-neuro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our projects seek to make cognitive neuroscience findings accessible to educators and facilitate collaborative work between educators and researchers.
The broad goals of our research are to encourage and strengthen dialogue between researchers, practitioners and the wider community to consolidate existing knowledge and generate new hypotheses to answer real-world questions in education and learning.
To achieve these goals we utilise a range of approaches, including language translations, open database platforms, meta-analyses and meta-analytic brain connectivity modelling, data-visualisation and focus group discussions.
This work has important implications in developing educator’s brain literacy and informing teaching and learning to support the growing population of diverse child and adult learners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Ongoing Project:&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Understanding functional relationships between socio-affective and neurocognitive brain networks in adults with ASD and ADHD to better inform learning for learners and educators: Towards maximising the adult learning potential&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developing educator’s Brain Literacy: BrainMap for Teacher Professional Development (DEV 01/21 AMG) (Funded by MOE-ERFP)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Completed Project:&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nie.edu.sg/research/projects/project/afd-07-16-zw&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Developing a translating educational neuroscience clearinghouse (TENC) for the differentiated instruction of diverse learners&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
