<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>On-going projects | The Clinical Brain Lab</title>
    <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/tag/on-going-projects/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/tag/on-going-projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>On-going projects</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/images/icon_hu30d0ad82a56c1708370149d7b9443316_148842_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>On-going projects</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/tag/on-going-projects/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biliteracy</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/biliteracy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/biliteracy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our research on biliteracy aims to better understand neural networks and the cognitive mechanisms underlying bilingualism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;measuring-the-brain-response-to-non-invasive-brain-stimulation&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Measuring the brain response to non-invasive brain stimulation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently in our lab, we are using fNIRS to explore changes in brain activity during brain stimulation and during cognitive tasks – i.e. reading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;fNIRS (functional near-infrared spectroscopy) is a non-invasive neuroimaging technique that measures brain responses by recording changes in the amount of oxygenated/deoxygenated blood. It works based on the principle of light scattering – the device sends high intensity beams of near-infrared light at the scalp and detects changes to amount of light absorbed within the brain. Mathematical algorithms are then applied to process the collected data to calculate changes in oxygenated/deoxygenated haemoglobin concentration. These changes are associated with changes in brain function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our project is activey looking for participants to take part!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./fNIRS-tDCS.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;investigating-the-bilingual-reading-network&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Investigating the Bilingual Reading Network&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chinese-English Bilinguals who had a history of dyslexia or are struggling in reading&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./biliteracy-dyslexia.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cerebellum and Cognition</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/cerebellum/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/cerebellum/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Description&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deception Neuroscience</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/deception-neuroscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/deception-neuroscience/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this project, we seek to utilize neuroimaging to clarify the neural basis of cognitive and emotion processing in deception for potential application towards deception detection in a real-world setting.
Neuroimaging research on deception has documented specific brain regions, and suggested potential neural network, associated with the cognitive processing of deception.
However, limited research has examined the neural correlates related to emotion processing when one deceives. Furthermore, to our knowledge, there is limited research examining the neural network that could
account for both cognitive and emotion processing in deception. Our first experiment will use &lt;strong&gt;functional magnetic resonance imaging (fMRI)&lt;/strong&gt; to address the present research gaps.
The second experiment will use electroencephalogram (EEG) to examine &lt;strong&gt;brain activity associated with deception at high temporal solution&lt;/strong&gt;.
The third experiment will focus on developing and validating a &lt;strong&gt;Deception Scale&lt;/strong&gt; that captures inter-individual differences in lying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;inter-individual-differences-in-deception-profile&#34;&gt;Inter-individual Differences in Deception Profile&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this study, we established a general framework to understanding deception as a dispositional trait, through developing and validating a short and reliable 16-item questionnaire.
Click 
&lt;a href=&#34;here&#34;&gt;http://www.ntu.edu.sg&lt;/a&gt; to read the final paper!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;fmri-and-deception&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;fMRI and Deception&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;fMRI is a safe, noninvasive imaging technology. Unlike x-rays, which use ionizing radiation, fMRI images are generated from a strong magnetic field and low-power radio-waves. Therefore, there is no risk of exposure to radiation in fMRI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;fMRI allows researchers to obtain images of brain activity over time, as participants complete various tasks. From these images, researchers get a better understanding of the brain areas that are involved in the tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;eeg-and-deception&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EEG and Deception&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EEG (Electroencephalogram) is a neuroimaging technique used to measure electrical activity at the scalp that reflects the neural activity in the brain. It is a real-time recording of neural activity with millisecond temporal resolution.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
