<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Annabel Chen | The Clinical Brain Lab</title>
    <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/author/annabel-chen/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/author/annabel-chen/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Annabel Chen</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/images/icon_hu30d0ad82a56c1708370149d7b9443316_148842_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Annabel Chen</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/author/annabel-chen/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Psychological Determinants of the Susceptibility to Fake News amidst the COVID-19 Pandemic</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2020_deception-covid-fakenews/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2020_deception-covid-fakenews/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As the COVID-19 outbreak spreads across the globe, the world is in parallel flooded by information reporting a wide range of facts, which veracity is not always verifiable.
Indeed, it has become increasingly apparent that the COVID-19 fake news pandemic is becoming just as viral as the outbreak of the disease itself, evidenced by the need for researchers
and authorities to track the spread of misinformation. As a consequence, the Ministry of Health in Singapore has even dedicated an entire website (See here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.moh.gov.sg/covid-19/clarifications&#34;&gt;https://www.moh.gov.sg/covid-19/clarifications&lt;/a&gt;) to debunk all instances of fake news.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-role-of-conspiracy-theories&#34;&gt;The Role of Conspiracy Theories&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the authorities are struggling to provide concrete explanations about the coronavirus, conspiracy theorists are quick to provide competing ones with confidence.
This has exaggerated the spread of fake news and conspiracy theories - beliefs that seek to explain the cause of an event by a hidden, wicked and unlawful scheme, without scientific support.
For instance, a theory that the new 5G technology causes the spread of coronavirus outbreak was widely circulated and peddled by conspiracy theorists.
Studies have shown that conspiracy theories are often endorsed by people who feel powerless. Their rejection of mainstream accounts and adoption of conspiracy explanations is an attempt to make sense of the world beyond their control (Swami &amp;amp; Furnham, 2010).
The uncertainties brought about by the COVID-19 pandemic might prompt people, especially individuals with higher schizotypal tendencies (characterized by suspicion, social anxiety and paranoid ideation), to engage in this sense-making mechanism, seeking alternative explanations
to regain their sense of control. People who have the tendency to adopt conspiracy theories have been found to rely more on intuition (Pennycook, Cheyne, Barr, Koehler &amp;amp; Fugelsang, 2015; Pennycook &amp;amp; Rand, 2018) and are hence more susceptible to fake news beliefs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-role-of-emotions&#34;&gt;The Role of Emotions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a global pandemic where the world is in a constant elevated state of anxiety, fake news beliefs can befall anyone for reasons beyond just the persistent cognitive biases that characterize conspiracist theorists.
People are often left feeling fearful and anxious due to the endless bombardment of pandemic news information, regardless of its accuracy.
Fake news on COVID-19 are especially emotionally engaging because they play on people’s helplessness by offering some miracle remedy or fueling anger towards authorities handling the situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A research team led by Gordon Pennycook, a researcher on the psychology of misinformation, found that individuals are more likely to perceive fake news headlines as accurate when they were in an emotional state (Martel et al., 2019). At the Clinical Brain Lab, we have started research into this area during the
Circuit Breaker period. We propose that the underlying factor driving susceptibility to fake news beliefs is not just the mere presence of negative affect, but how one regulates these emotions.
This refers to the ability to control one’s emotional state, such as considering alternative interpretations of an otherwise negative situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the context of the COVID-19 pandemic, an important aspect of emotion regulation is being able to navigate through the uncertainties of the future. With future plans now at a standstill and emotions running high, we become less tolerant of uncertainty and feel more helpless about our circumstances.
Poor self-control makes us cognitively lazy, believing something because “it feels right” and aligned with our emotions. Fast, intuitive processing thus often takes precedence over effortful and reflective thinking, of which the latter is needed to discern whether a piece of news is real or fake (Pennycook &amp;amp; Rand, 2019).
We are thus more vulnerable to engaging in fake news than we think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;our-research&#34;&gt;Our Research&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As it is important to delineate the psychological determinants of the belief in fake news as part of a global effort in combating misinformation, Prof Annabel Chen together with Research Fellow Dr Dominique Makowski and research assistants (Pham Thanh Tam and Lau Zen Juen) are currently conducting an investigation into the spread of COVID-19 fake news in Singapore.
Specifically, this study seeks to examine whether the belief in conspiracy theories and one’s ability to regulate emotions are related to one’s tendency to fall prey to fake news.
This study is pre-registered at 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://osf.io/7d3xh/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;OSF&lt;/a&gt; and currently undergoing data analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Active Aging Lifestyle</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/ageing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/ageing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Combining both cognitive and exercise training in an intervention program may be advantageous to enhance cognitive and physical functions.
However, this approach has yet to be well researched and implemented. Given the hot and humid climate and community environments (e.g., sidewalks and street traffic) in Singapore, common aerobic exercises such as walking and jogging may not be the first choice for sedentary older adults in Singapore.
Therefore, we proposed to develop an intervention program (&lt;strong&gt;ExCITE: Exercise-Cognition Integrated Training for Enhancement&lt;/strong&gt;) that incorporates both cognitive and physical exercise components that can be easily implemented and weaved into the lifestyles of our aging population.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Behevioural and Neural Correlates of Deception</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/deception/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/deception/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Traditional lie detection as used in polygraph test is based on examining one&amp;rsquo;s physiological arousal (measuring skin conductance,
heart rate, and respiration) to infer lying. However, such physiological arousal may merely be reflecting anxiety and fear during a polygraph examination,
rather than lying per se.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As physiological arousal could not be used to accurately infer lying, researchers are urged to further look into the mental processes related to lying.
To date, different neurophysiological signals, including functional magnetic resonance imaging (fMRI) and event-related potentials (ERP) have been studied for possible application to index deception.
Past studies have shown evidences that strongly supporting the hypothesis that deception requires the coordination of multiple cognitive processes and thus is more cognitively taxing than truth telling.
Despite the positive findings, previous studies were often criticized for not capturing lying as it exists in the real world. Indeed, majority of the experimental paradigms required participants to lie about perceptual
stimuli or memorized materials. More importantly, unlike lying in the real world, the lies generated in research labs were often not spontaneous but instructed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To increase the translational value of the research in deception and lie detection, we aim to investigate the neural correlates of lying using paradigms that can elicit lying similar to those in the real world.
In addition, we also seek to explore the structure of dispositional deception by developing and validating a short and reliable questionnaire to characterize individuals&#39; lying patterns.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bilingual Reading Networks</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/reading-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/reading-network/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our projects aim to elucidate the neurocognitive mechanisms underlying typical and impaired reading in bilinguals.
We use a combination of behavioural assessment and neuroimaging techniques to investigate the neural reading networks for bilingual readers from a variety of language profiles, across early childhood and adulthood.
Our projects will shed light on the impact of critical factors (e.g., orthographic depth of scripts, auditory perception skills) on the bilingual reading networks. Our findings will provide implications for neuroscience-informed remediation of reading difficulties for bilingual readers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ongoing projects:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Effective Biliteracy: The Impact of Script Sets on Bilingual Reading Networks for Typical and Atypical Readers (funded by NTU-JHU Collaborative Grant)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reading Brains Project (funded by National Research Foundation)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Promoting Effective Biliteracy</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/pebbles/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/pebbles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The project aims to develop an early screening and training programme to promote balanced bilingual development and biliteracy attainment in early childhood.
Using a multimodal approach, we will identify early neural, cognitive, and environmental predictors in preschool years for later bilingual and biliteracy development.
We will evaluate the neurocognitive effects of different training programmes on enhancing biliteracy development. The knowledge gained from the project will broaden our understanding of the neurocognitive development of language and reading networks in young bilinguals.
The findings will have significant implications for early screening and effective training for promoting balanced bilingual and biliteracy development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ongoing project:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Promoting Effective Biliteracy in Early Childhood: A Systematic Screening and Training Programme for Balanced Bilingual Development (funded by Singapore Millennium Foundation)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Structure of Deception: Validation of the Lying Profile Questionnaire</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2020_deception-scale/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2020_deception-scale/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Translating neuroscience for educators</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/translate-neuro/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/project/translate-neuro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our projects seek to make cognitive neuroscience findings accessible to educators and facilitate collaborative work between educators and researchers.
The broad goals of our research are to encourage and strengthen dialogue between researchers, practitioners and the wider community to consolidate existing knowledge and generate new hypotheses to answer real-world questions in education and learning.
To achieve these goals we utilise a range of approaches, including language translations, open database platforms, meta-analyses and meta-analytic brain connectivity modelling, data-visualisation and focus group discussions.
This work has important implications in developing educator’s brain literacy and informing teaching and learning to support the growing population of diverse child and adult learners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ongoing Project:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Understanding functional relationships between socio-affective and neurocognitive brain networks in adults with ASD and ADHD to better inform learning for learners and educators: Towards maximising the adult learning potential&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Completed Project:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nie.edu.sg/research/projects/project/afd-07-16-zw&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Developing a translating educational neuroscience clearinghouse (TENC) for the differentiated instruction of diverse learners&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>i-SATA: A MATLAB based toolbox to estimate current density generated by transcranial direct current stimulation in an individual brain</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2020_isata/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2020_isata/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The role of primary motor cortex: More than movement execution</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2020_m1-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2020_m1-review/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indices of effect existence and significance in the Bayesian framework</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2019_bayesian/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2019_bayesian/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maximizing dissimilarity in resting state detects heterogeneous subtypes in healthy population associated with high substance use and problems in antisocial personality</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2020_rsfmri-subtypes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2020_rsfmri-subtypes/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Translating education neuroscience for teachers</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2019_learning-translating/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2019_learning-translating/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brain literacy empowers educators to meet diverse learner needs</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2019_learning-brain-literacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2019_learning-brain-literacy/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simulation analyses of tDcS montages for the investigation of dorsal and ventral pathways</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2020_tdcs-montages-simulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2020_tdcs-montages-simulation/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cerebro-cerebellar pathways for verbal working memory</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2019_cerebellum-working-memory-pathways/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2019_cerebellum-working-memory-pathways/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working memory, age and education: A lifespan fMRI study</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2018_ageing-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2018_ageing-education/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Functional connectivity of resting-state, working memory and inhibition networks in perceived stress</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2018_stress-working-memory/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2018_stress-working-memory/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The role of regional heterogeneity in age-related differences in functional hemispheric asymmetry: an fMRI study</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2018_ageing-asymmetry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2018_ageing-asymmetry/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Frontal-subcortical circuitry in social attachment and relationships: A cross-sectional fMRI ALE meta-analysis</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2017_meta-analysis-hot-cool/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2017_meta-analysis-hot-cool/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reconciling individual differences with collective needs: The juxtaposition of sociopolitical and neuroscience perspectives on remediation and compensation of student skill deficits</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2016_learning-remediation-compensation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2016_learning-remediation-compensation/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modality specificity in the cerebro-cerebellar neurocircuitry during working memory</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2016_cerebellum-working-memory-modality/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2016_cerebellum-working-memory-modality/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A comprehensive analysis of connectivity and aging over the adult life span</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2018_ageing-connectivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2018_ageing-connectivity/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Temporal dynamics of visual working memory</title>
      <link>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2016_cerebellum-working-memory-dynamics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://clinicalbrainlab.github.io/publication/2016_cerebellum-working-memory-dynamics/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
