<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publication on The Clinical Brain Lab</title>
    <link>/publication/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Publication on The Clinical Brain Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 16:03:15 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/publication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Cerebro-cerebellar pathways for verbal working memory</title>
      <link>/publication/cc-pathway/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 16:03:15 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/cc-pathway/</guid>
      <description>Verbal working memory involves holding verbal information in short-term memory. Two cerebro-cerebellar networks for verbal working memory have been proposed: (1) fronto-superior cerebellar network associated with controlling and updating speech-related information, and (2) parieto-inferior cerebellar network associated with storing speech-related information briefly. Sobczak-Edmans and colleagues (2019) examined the structural and functional connectivity of these cerebro-cerebellar networks. Using diffusion spectrum imaging tractography, they reconstructed white matter tracts in: (1) the left inferior frontal gyrus via the pons to the right superior cerebellum, and (2) the left inferior parietal lobule via the pons to the right inferior cerebellum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indices of Effect Existence and Significance in the Bayesian Framework</title>
      <link>/publication/bayesian-framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 16:03:15 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/bayesian-framework/</guid>
      <description>The Bayesian framework is increasingly believed to address some issues with the frequentist framework, especially the misuse and misinterpretation of p-values that has contributed to the reproducibility crisis. While the Bayesian framework offers several alternative indices for the frequentist p-value, there is a lack of consensus and guidelines to help researchers decide which indices to use and understand the meaning of the values. Makowski and colleagues (2019) compared several Bayesian indices by simulating two widely used models in psychological sciences.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>